<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Namecoin</title>
    <description><!--Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
--></description>
    <link>https://www.namecoin.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.namecoin.org/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en</language>
    <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 08:36:39 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 08:36:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.namecoin.org/images/logo.png</url>
      <title>Namecoin</title>
      <link>https://www.namecoin.org/</link>
      <width>134</width>
      <height>25</height>
    </image>
    
      <item>
        <title>Enhancements to IPFS &amp; IPNS: A Closer Look at the Latest Updates</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Several new Electrum-NMC enhancements have been added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-dedicated-gui-for-ipfs--ipns&quot;&gt;The Dedicated GUI for IPFS &amp;amp; IPNS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, interacting with IPFS required the creation of TXT records and knowledge of IPFS DNSLink. However, with the introduction of a dedicated GUI, users now have a more user-friendly option, available in the address tab. To learn more about DNSLink and its use of DNS TXT records to map names to IPFS addresses or IPNS names, refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.ipfs.tech/concepts/dnslink/&quot;&gt;IPFS DNS documentation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/IPFS-GUI-Introduction.png&quot; alt=&quot;IPFS Images&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;https://www.namecoin.org/files/videos/docs/ipfs/brave-ipfs.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot; /&gt;
Demo video of Namecoin + IPFS in Brave.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;added-option-for-value-encoding&quot;&gt;Added Option for Value Encoding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When registering names, there is now an option to pass values as binary, encoded in hexadecimal format. This enhancement provides greater flexibility and control for developers and power users, allowing them to represent domain name values in a more efficient and versatile manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/Binary-Encoding-Values-GUI.png&quot; alt=&quot;Binary Encoding (value)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gui-testing&quot;&gt;GUI Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For GUI testing, we validate the GUI form’s build process and execute regression tests, which helps us identify any errors in the files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;windows-binaries-testing&quot;&gt;Windows Binaries Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We validate the integrity of the build process and conduct regression tests on these binaries to ensure their functionality and detect any potential issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s NGI Assure Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2024/04/29/ipfs-value-binary-encoding.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2024/04/29/ipfs-value-binary-encoding.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Electrum-NMC v4.0.6 Released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve released Electrum-NMC v4.0.6. The changelog will probably be posted after 37C3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, you can download it at the &lt;a href=&quot;/download/betas/#electrum-nmc&quot;&gt;Beta Downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s NGI0 Discovery Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2023/12/23/electrum-nmc-v4.0.6-released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2023/12/23/electrum-nmc-v4.0.6-released.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>Releases</category>
        
        <category>Electrum Releases</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin will be at 37C3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After a lengthy pandemic-induced hiatus, C3 is finally back this year, and we’re happy to announce that three Namecoin developers will be at &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.ccc.de/congress/2023/wiki/index.php/Main_Page&quot;&gt;37C3 (the 37th Chaos Communication Congress)&lt;/a&gt; in Hamburg, December 27-30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excitingly, one of our developers in attendance (Hugo Landau) will be giving a talk in the main track (not a Cluster track); &lt;a href=&quot;https://fahrplan.events.ccc.de/congress/2023/fahrplan/events/11781.html&quot;&gt;the details for that talk are here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect to give some additional talks and workshops at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://decentral.community/&quot;&gt;Critical Decentralization Cluster (CDC)&lt;/a&gt;, however, the details of those events are still in flux and will probably not be announced until shortly before the beginning of the Congress; keep an eye on &lt;a href=&quot;https://frab.riat.at/en/37c3/public/schedule&quot;&gt;the CDC schedule&lt;/a&gt;. Recordings and live-streams may happen as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, Namecoin has participated in C3 as a Project of the Monero Assembly. We’re excited to announce that this year, Namecoin has been upgraded to a full Assembly of our own. Namecoin and Monero remain excellent friends, but everyone agreed that this year, the time was right for us to branch out as an independent Assembly. Also thanks go out to our friends at &lt;a href=&quot;https://replicant.us/&quot;&gt;The Replicant Assembly&lt;/a&gt;, who are once again facilitating Namecoin’s participation. We’re looking forward to the Congress!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2023/12/21/37c3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2023/12/21/37c3.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin Receives 40.1k EUR in Additional Funding from NLnet Foundation’s NGI Assure Fund and European Commission</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re happy to announce that Namecoin is receiving 40,100 EUR (roughly 44,134 USD) in additional funding from &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnet.nl/&quot;&gt;NLnet Foundation&lt;/a&gt;’s NGI Assure Fund.  If you’re unfamiliar with NLnet, you might want to read &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnet.nl/foundation/&quot;&gt;about NLnet Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, or just take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnet.nl/thema/index.html&quot;&gt;the projects they’ve funded over the years&lt;/a&gt; (you might see some familiar names).  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnet.nl/assure/&quot;&gt;NGI Assure Fund&lt;/a&gt; is managed by NLnet and funded by the European Commission, the executive branch of the European Union, through their Next Generation Internet intitiative.  This new funding is focused on Electrum-NMC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will use this funding to work on the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved sandboxing for better security.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved test coverage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved domain management GUI for better UX.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Compact on-chain storage for better scalability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Linux packaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work will principally be done by developers Robert Nganga and Jeremy Rand (who is the author of this post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank the awesome people at NLnet Foundation for the continued vote of confidence, as well as the European Commision for their support of a Next Generation Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be posting updates regularly as development proceeds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2023/12/21/namecoin-additional-funding-from-nlnet-ngi-assure.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2023/12/21/namecoin-additional-funding-from-nlnet-ngi-assure.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Binary Encoding Support and Testing Enhancements</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Electrum-NMC has recently undergone significant improvements aimed at refining the user experience and expanding functionality. The most prominent changes involve the introduction of three distinct tabs within the graphical user interface (GUI): Hex, Domain, and ASCII. The Hex tab now serves as a dedicated space for users to interact with the hexadecimal representations of names, providing a standardized and transparent view of binary data. The Domain tab focuses on simplifying interactions by allowing users to employ a simpler format like “name.bit” instead of the original “d/name” format. Meanwhile, the ASCII tab preserves the original format of registration, ensuring compatibility for users who prefer the original format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;graceful-handling-of-invalid-ascii&quot;&gt;Graceful Handling of Invalid ASCII&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the event of invalid ASCII input, the system gracefully handles the situation. This allows valid hexadecimal data that is not a valid ASCII representation to be managed without disrupting the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;appimage-binaries-testing&quot;&gt;AppImage Binaries Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A dedicated testing pipeline has been introduced for AppImage binaries. The regression tests run on these binaries to verify their functionality and identify any potential issues. This meticulous approach ensures that users working with AppImage binaries can trust in the stability and performance of Electrum-NMC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;macos-tarball-binaries-testing&quot;&gt;MacOS Tarball Binaries Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For MacOS, a specific testing environment has been created to run regression tests on the tarball binaries. This testing setup not only verifies the integrity of the binaries but also ensures that Electrum-NMC performs seamlessly in a MacOS environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These testing procedures cover a range of scenarios and use cases, providing a robust framework to identify and address any potential issues before they impact end-users. The commitment to thorough testing underscores the project’s dedication to delivering a reliable and high-performance cryptocurrency wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s NGI Assure Fund.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2023/12/04/binary-encoding.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2023/12/04/binary-encoding.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>SOCKSification: Outreachy Internship Progress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;SOCKSification refers to the process of rerouting network traffic from an application via a SOCKS proxy server. This method is frequently used for security, anonymity, and circumventing network constraints. There are numerous techniques for SOCKSification, but in this article, we will focus on two main approaches that were considered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first method includes intercepting the application’s connect and send system calls. When an application wants to connect to a remote server, it performs a connect system call with the target IP address and port specified. Following that, the send system call is used to transfer data through the established connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this method, we intercept the connect syscall and change the target IP address and port to those of the SOCKS proxy server. Then we intercept the send syscall which will contain a pointer (in tracee memory space) to the buffer that the application wants to send. We can prepend a SOCKS handshake to that buffer.  While this method can accomplish SOCKSification, it necessitates changing the tracee’s memory, which is not memory safe and might cause security problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second method, which is safer, includes utilizing the pidfd getfd capability, which was added to Linux v5.6, to duplicate the file descriptor of the established connection. When an application connects, the connect syscall returns a file descriptor, which may be used to transmit and receive data through the connection. We can replicate the file descriptor from the tracee to the tracer using the pidfd getfd functionality without having to touch the tracee’s memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To SOCKSify the program, we intercept the connect syscall and change the target IP address and port to those of the SOCKS proxy server. The exit of the connect syscall, which returns the file descriptor of the established socket, is then intercepted. Using pidfd getfd, we copy this file descriptor to the tracer and execute a SOCKS5 handshake with the tracer’s socket. After the handshake, we resume the tracee, and all future network traffic gets SOCKSified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SOCKSification occurs in the function &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/robertmin1/heteronculous-horklump/blob/test-3/main.go#L412&quot;&gt;Socksify.&lt;/a&gt; This function allows an application running on a Linux system to use the SOCKS5 protocol to route network traffic through a proxy server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The function begins by checking whether the “one circuit” configuration option is set. If not, it initializes a set of authentication data consisting of 10 SOCKS user+pass pairs. Each connection is then assigned to a randomly selected slot from those 10. This is important in order to prevent vulnerability to a Sybil attack. Applications that connect to a P2P network (such as the Bitcoin network) may need to avoid using the same Tor circuit for all connections. Otherwise, a malicious Tor exit relay can block the application’s view of the network. Furthermore, using a different Tor circuit for each connection can also be helpful for things like download managers, as it avoids slowdowns caused by an unlucky slow Tor circuit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The function then reads the IP address and port number of the address we’re diverting from exit_addr, a thread-safe map. The address for each process that requires the SOCKS5 proxy is saved in the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The function then opens the file descriptor associated with the program’s network connection. With the os.NewFile function, the file descriptor is utilized to construct a new file object. The net.FileConn function is then called on the file object to generate a net.Conn object. This enables the application to communicate with its network connection using the standard net package rather than the lower-level system calls that were used to establish the connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The NewClient function is called, as well as the client’s Dial method. This creates a new client containing details such as authentication credentials and timeout values. The Dial method is then called, which carries out the redirecting. To listen to an existing net.Conn , we are currently utilizing a customized version of SOCKS5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;relevant-links&quot;&gt;Relevant Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/txthinking/socks5&quot;&gt;SOCKS5 Repository&lt;/a&gt; We are planning to contribute the changes to the main SOCKS5 repository (Allowing the Dial Function to listen to an existing net.Conn file)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/namecoin/heteronculous-horklump&quot;&gt;Heteronculous-horklump Repository&lt;/a&gt;: The main codebase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/robertmin1/heteronculous-horklump&quot;&gt;Temporary Heteronculous-horklump Repository&lt;/a&gt;: Contains the SOCKSification work in progress, which will be soon be merged upstream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.outreachy.org/&quot;&gt;Outreachy&lt;/a&gt; under the Tor Project umbrella.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2023/02/23/socksification-outreachy-internship.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2023/02/23/socksification-outreachy-internship.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Outreachy Internship Progress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings! I wanted to provide an overall update on the project’s progress. We have successfully implemented the ability to detect the IP address and port that socket system calls are sending data to, as well as the capability to block system calls that are sending data to an IP address and port that is not the desired proxy. Additionally, we have added an option to kill the application if a proxy leak occurs, which is useful for manual QA testing, and an option to allow proxy leaks but log any that occur, which is useful for automated testing of applications. Furthermore, we have included the capability to use the environment variables that Tor Browser uses, such as TOR_SOCKS_PORT, to determine the desired proxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, we are currently in the process of implementing SOCKSification, which involves intercepting the connect syscall’s entry point, modifying the destination IP/Port, and capturing the established socket’s file descriptor through the exit of the connect syscall. A SOCKS5 handshake is then performed on the file descriptor. Afterwards, socks authentication enforcement and support of UDP proxies will be implemented. Socks authentication enforcement will detect if the tracee is using SOCKS without an appropriate username/password (stream isolation leak)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program instructions are manipulated using flags through &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hlandau/easyconfig/tree/v1.0.18&quot;&gt;easyconfig&lt;/a&gt; which enables easy manipulation of arguments. Logging is done using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hlandau/xlog&quot;&gt;xlog&lt;/a&gt; which provides different options for logging. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/u-root/u-root/tree/v0.10.0/pkg/strace&quot;&gt;U-root&lt;/a&gt; was preferred for tracing since it is easier to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suggestions are much welcomed! &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/namecoin/heteronculous-horklump&quot;&gt;Project Repository&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/11/29/introducing-intern-robert-nganga.html&quot;&gt;Project Summary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.outreachy.org/&quot;&gt;Outreachy&lt;/a&gt; under the Tor Project umbrella.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2023/01/29/outreachy-internship-update.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2023/01/29/outreachy-internship-update.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Internship Progress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Greetings! I completed the initial tasks for the internship during the first week, where I utilized and experimented with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pkg.go.dev/github.com/u-root/u-root/pkg/strace&quot;&gt;u-root strace package.&lt;/a&gt; The first tasks were to launch a program using ptrace and detect socket system calls. The first task was straightforward, requiring only the usage of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/u-root/u-root/blob/v0.10.0/pkg/strace/tracer.go#L156&quot;&gt;Trace Function.&lt;/a&gt; For the latter, it included utilizing a map to determine if the system call is a socket syscall and then informing the user if it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, I worked on the main tasks, which included determining the IP address and port on which socket system calls send data. I did this by first filtering out syscalls that initiate a socket connection, then sending the syscall through the &lt;a href=&quot;https://pkg.go.dev/github.com/u-root/u-root/pkg/strace#SysCallEnter&quot;&gt;SysCallEnter function.&lt;/a&gt; This returns a string containing the Address and Port, which we then extract using string slicing. Better methods will be developed to replace string slicing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While resolving some of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/namecoin/heteronculous-horklump/issues&quot;&gt;issues&lt;/a&gt;, I am now working on blocking system calls that transfer data to an IP address+port that is not the targeted proxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by Outreachy under the Tor Project umbrella.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Publishing of this post was delayed by infrastructure issues on Namecoin Project’s end; we apologize for the delay, which was not due to any fault of Robert.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2023/01/10/week-one-of-internship-robert-nganga.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2023/01/10/week-one-of-internship-robert-nganga.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Outreachy Blog #1: Introduce Yourself</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! My name is Robert, an Outreachy Intern. I spend most of my days gaming, coding and learning. I’ve been very interested in open-source projects, and two months after contributing to Namecoin, I started my internship. For the two months, the experience has been very enjoyable and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-core-values&quot;&gt;My Core Values&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Integrity: I believe in being honest and transparent in all my actions and decisions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Innovation: I value creativity and constantly strive to find new and better ways of doing things.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Collaboration: I believe in working together with others to achieve common goals and create successful outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-motivated-me-to-apply-to-outreachy&quot;&gt;What motivated me to apply to Outreachy&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several factors influenced my decision to apply to Outreachy. To begin, I am really interested in open source and want to obtain practical experience in this subject. Outreachy is a fantastic chance for people like me to contribute to open source projects while learning from experienced mentors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, I am enthusiastic in learning new things and honing my talents. Outreachy provides a structured internship program in which I may work on difficult projects while developing my technical and professional abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I feel Outreachy will give me with beneficial networking chances. I am looking forward to meeting other Outreachy participants and mentors and developing contacts that will benefit my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by Outreachy under the Tor Project umbrella.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@mindo.robert1/outreachy-blog-1-introduce-yourself-ae45357227&quot;&gt;Cross-posted from Medium.&lt;/a&gt;  The cross-posting was delayed by infrastructure issues on Namecoin Project’s end; we apologize for the delay, which was not due to any fault of Robert.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2023/01/09/outreachy-blog-1-introduce-yourself.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2023/01/09/outreachy-blog-1-introduce-yourself.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ncp11 Nightly Builds Now Available</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;More work has been done with pkcs11mod and ncp11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, a bunch of additional missing functions have beeen added to p11mod.  A lot of these functions came from Oureachy applicants, since I used pkcs11mod as a contribution task repo for Outreachy.  Some of these previously-missing functions may be useful to smartcard use cases, so if you’ve been holding off on touching p11mod for a smartcard project, it may be time to look again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I discussed the p11 API with Miek, specifically some shortcomings that make it hard for Namecoin to emulate the p11 API.  We’ve agreed that Namecoin will maintain a fork with API changes for about 6 months, and then I’ll submit the changes upstream once I’m satisfied that it works in production.  The changes have a Concept ACK.  p11mod has beeen updated to use the fork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The p11trustmod library is fully working now, although there are no integration tests for it yet.  But how did I test it, then?  The ncp11 codebase has also now been rewritten to use p11trustmod!  Currently it only does positive overrides, and I’ve only tested it with Firefox on GNU/Linux, but it works.  For reference, the old ncp11 was 1351 lines of code; the rewrite is only 228.  Not a bad result; seems the abstraction work done on p11mod and p11trustmod was well-worth it.  There is currently a quirk where ncp11 has to mark intermediate CA’s as trusted; only marking the Namecoin root CA as trusted does not make the certs pass validation.  I intend to debug this later, but trusting intermediate CA’s is harmless here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone who wants to play around with this, ncp11 Nightly builds are now available on the Beta Downloads page.  You’ll also need a Nightly version of Encaya, as a bunch of bugfixes were needed on the Encaya side.  Installation instructions don’t exist yet, but if you know how to install Encaya, and you know how to install PKCS#11 modules into Firefox (e.g. for smartcards), you should be able to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s Internet Hardening Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2022/11/30/ncp11-nightly-builds.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2022/11/30/ncp11-nightly-builds.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
