<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Namecoin</title>
    <description><!--Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
--></description>
    <link>https://www.namecoin.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.namecoin.org/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en</language>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 15:06:42 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 15:06:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.namecoin.org/images/logo.png</url>
      <title>Namecoin</title>
      <link>https://www.namecoin.org/</link>
      <width>134</width>
      <height>25</height>
    </image>
    
      <item>
        <title>ncp11 Nightly Builds Now Available</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;More work has been done with pkcs11mod and ncp11.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, a bunch of additional missing functions have beeen added to p11mod.  A lot of these functions came from Oureachy applicants, since I used pkcs11mod as a contribution task repo for Outreachy.  Some of these previously-missing functions may be useful to smartcard use cases, so if you’ve been holding off on touching p11mod for a smartcard project, it may be time to look again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I discussed the p11 API with Miek, specifically some shortcomings that make it hard for Namecoin to emulate the p11 API.  We’ve agreed that Namecoin will maintain a fork with API changes for about 6 months, and then I’ll submit the changes upstream once I’m satisfied that it works in production.  The changes have a Concept ACK.  p11mod has beeen updated to use the fork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The p11trustmod library is fully working now, although there are no integration tests for it yet.  But how did I test it, then?  The ncp11 codebase has also now been rewritten to use p11trustmod!  Currently it only does positive overrides, and I’ve only tested it with Firefox on GNU/Linux, but it works.  For reference, the old ncp11 was 1351 lines of code; the rewrite is only 228.  Not a bad result; seems the abstraction work done on p11mod and p11trustmod was well-worth it.  There is currently a quirk where ncp11 has to mark intermediate CA’s as trusted; only marking the Namecoin root CA as trusted does not make the certs pass validation.  I intend to debug this later, but trusting intermediate CA’s is harmless here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For anyone who wants to play around with this, ncp11 Nightly builds are now available on the Beta Downloads page.  You’ll also need a Nightly version of Encaya, as a bunch of bugfixes were needed on the Encaya side.  Installation instructions don’t exist yet, but if you know how to install Encaya, and you know how to install PKCS#11 modules into Firefox (e.g. for smartcards), you should be able to figure it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s Internet Hardening Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2022/11/30/ncp11-nightly-builds.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2022/11/30/ncp11-nightly-builds.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Introducing Namecoin's New Intern, Robert Nganga</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hey everyone, Jeremy here.  We’re happy to announce that Namecoin has accepted an intern via &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.outreachy.org/&quot;&gt;Outreachy&lt;/a&gt; (we are participating under the Tor Project umbrella).  Robert Nganga will be funded to work on a new project that I think both the Namecoin and Tor communities will find exciting.  Huge thanks are due to Tor Project for taking us under their wing for this internship.  I don’t want to steal his thunder any more than I already have, so I’m going to turn over the remainder of this post to Robert to tell you about his project – please join us in welcoming him to the Namecoin community!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greetings, I am pleased to join the Namecoin team as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.outreachy.org/&quot;&gt;Outreachy&lt;/a&gt; Intern after two months of contributing to Namecoin. I’ll be working on developing a tool that can identify and prevent proxy leaks. I’ll be using ptrace to intercept network socket system calls in a Tor-using application and block them if they constitute a proxy leak. Given the substantial threats posed by proxy leaks, the technology will improve security and privacy while resolving current problems with the technologies already in use. For instance, torsocks, an LD_PRELOAD-based program that intercepts calls to the network functions of the standard C library, is incompatible with statically linked software, such as the majority of Golang-written applications (Given that Golang is frequently used for security-conscious applications, this is particularly problematic) Transparent proxy tools like Whonix can result in usage of multiple applications being traceable to the same user, since you can’t easily enforce stream isolation (degrading anonymity into much weaker pseudonymity)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, prior Namecoin development such as the Namecoin support in Tor Browser, was for a period slowed down by manual audits for proxy leaks. In the future, the tool will prevent such bottlenecks. This ptrace approach has a &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/JeremyRand/heteronculous&quot;&gt;crude proof-of-concept&lt;/a&gt; in Bash, which was developed by the Namecoin team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project will be mentored by Jeremy Rand, who will also provide any support required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by Outreachy under the Tor Project umbrella.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2022/11/29/introducing-intern-robert-nganga.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2022/11/29/introducing-intern-robert-nganga.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand and Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Anonymity Improvements in Electrum-NMC v4.0.6</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Electrum-NMC v4.0.6 (soon to be released) brings some long-awaited anonymity improvements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;automatic-coin-control-for-names&quot;&gt;Automatic Coin Control for Names&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first described this feature in &lt;a href=&quot;/2018/03/19/34c3-slides-videos.html&quot;&gt;my 34C3 presentation on anonymity&lt;/a&gt;.  There’s not much else to say here; my presentation covers how the feature works and why that design was chosen.  The delay between 34C3 and implementation is due to the preferences expressed by the Tor developers, hopefully it was worth the wait.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whonixtails-support&quot;&gt;Whonix/Tails Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Various anonymous OS’s such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whonix.org/&quot;&gt;Whonix&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://tails.boum.org/&quot;&gt;Tails&lt;/a&gt; come with Tor preconfigured.  A major component of how these OS’s handle preconfiguration is via environment variables that tell Tor-friendly applications such as Tor Browser and OnionShare where Tor’s SOCKS port is.  Electrum-NMC now supports these environment variables, so it will automatically use the correct SOCKS port (with stream isolation) on Whonix and Tails instead of relying on transproxying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of this work, I engaged with the Tor Applications Team on improving the specifications for Tor-friendly applications.  This work has been slower than hoped, but some major improvements have already worked their way through the review process, and I expect to deliver more improvements to these specifications in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apparmor-sandboxing-support&quot;&gt;AppArmor Sandboxing Support&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides environment variables, another trick that Whonix uses to Torify applications is usage of AppArmor to blacklist traffic that doesn’t go through Tor’s SOCKS port.  This works by having Tor listen on a Unix domain socket, and then blacklisting IP sockets via AppArmor; standard filesystem ACL’s take care of the rest.  Electrum-NMC now supports connecting to a SOCKS proxy via a Unix domain socket, so it should now be possible to enforce Torification via AppArmor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, no one has written such an AppArmor policy for Electrum-NMC; this will be the subject of future work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s NGI0 Discovery Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2022/10/28/anonymity-improvements-in-electrum-nmc-v4.0.6.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2022/10/28/anonymity-improvements-in-electrum-nmc-v4.0.6.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Changes to name_show in Electrum-NMC Protocol v1.4.3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my 36C3 presentation (seems so long ago…), I mentioned some future changes I wanted to make to the Electrum-NMC protocol.  Some of these changes have recently been implemented:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;verifying-unconfirmed-transactions&quot;&gt;Verifying Unconfirmed Transactions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For security reasons, Electrum-NMC has historically required 12 confirmations before it accepts a name transaction.  Unfortunately, waiting 2 hours (on average) for a name update to take effect is not great UX, and also introduces its own security issues (e.g. it means that TLS revocations are unnecessarily delayed).  When evaluating security of name transactions, there are two different attacks that we need to consider:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hijacking attacks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Double-spend attacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hijacking attacks occur when a malicious miner mines a Namecoin block with an invalid scriptSig, which (if accepted) would allow them to hijack an arbitrary name without any participation from the name owner.  In contrast, double-spend attacks occur when a malicious name owner signs two different name updates with the same input, which (if accepted) would allow one of those name updates to be accepted even though only the other update is part of the longest blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In practice, while any name could be targeted by a hijacking attack, only names that have recently been transferred to a new owner can be targeted by a double-spend attack.  (Double-spending a name that you still own doesn’t really confer any benefit.)  Since the vast majority of names have not been transferred in the last 12 blocks, if we can prevent hijacking attacks, we can accept the risk of double-spend attacks, since the latter can easily be mitigated by waiting 12 blocks from receiving a name transfer before using that name for critical purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can we do this?  Ryan Castellucci proposed many years ago that we could verify the scriptSigs of recent name updates, chaining them back to a previous name update that has sufficient DMMS confirmation (i.e. 12 blocks).  I have now implemented this in Electrum-NMC Protocol v1.4.3; Electrum-NMC will retrieve recent updates to a name (from 1 to 11 confirmations) and verify scriptSigs to chain them back to the most recent update with at least 12 confirmations.  The result is that name updates now take effect in 1 block (~10 minutes) instead of 12 blocks (~2 hours).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;checkpoint-verification&quot;&gt;Checkpoint Verification&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the inherent problems with the SPV threat model is that it only verifies DMMS signatures (attached to blocks), not scriptSigs (attached to transactions).  This means that an attacker with a majority of hashrate can mine invalid blocks (e.g. that hijack names) that will appear valid to SPV clients.  Full nodes are, of course, immune to this, since they check scriptSigs on all transactions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, full nodes have a much longer IBD duration, and also are much more resource-intensive.  Can an SPV client verify scriptSigs on the transactions it cares about?  In Bitcoinland, this is not really feasible, because the fungible nature of bitcoins means that you’d have to verify every transitive input to every transaction you care about, which would probably be exponential with respect to the verification depth.  However, in Namecoinland, we don’t have this problem.  The nonfungible nature of Namecoin names means that the number of transitive inputs grows linearly, not exponentially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, we can reuse the scriptSig chaining trick to chain the latest confirmed name update back to a previous update that was committed to in the checkpoint (if such an update exists).  This means that in order to hijack a name that existed at the checkpoint height, an attacker would need to compromise both a majority of hashrate &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; the full node used to generate the checkpoint.  I’ve implemented this in Electrum-NMC Protocol v1.4.3 as well; Electrum-NMC will retrieve all updates for a name going back to just before the checkpoint height, and verify the chain of scriptSigs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;one-round-trip&quot;&gt;One Round Trip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electrum-NMC’s protocol has always been inefficient for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;name_show&lt;/code&gt;, because it needed to issue 4 commands to the ElectrumX server per name:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get the latest name update txid.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get the transaction preimage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get the Merkle proof tying the txid to the block header.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get the Merkle proof tying the block header to the checkpoint.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter 3 of those could be issued in parallel, but that still means a best case of 2 round trips per lookup (and the best case was not always achieved in practice).  Especially over Tor, this extra latency is a major UX problem.  This inefficiency was a result of the upstream Electrum protocol for Bitcoin not being designed for Namecoin’s use cases.  As of Electrum-NMC Protocol v1.4.3, there is a dedicated command for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;name_show&lt;/code&gt;, which combines the above 4 commands into 1, thus cutting down the lookup time to a single round trip.  The above scriptSig-related features are also integrated into the dedicated command, so retrieving the extra transactions does not incur any extra round trips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;future-optimizations&quot;&gt;Future Optimizations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electrum-NMC Protocol v1.4.3 also allows the ElectrumX server to send hint data for names other than the requested one.  For example, if &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;d/wikileaks&lt;/code&gt; imports from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dd/wikileaks&lt;/code&gt;, the server might return data for both &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;d/wikileaks&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dd/wikileaks&lt;/code&gt; when the client requests the former, thus saving a round trip if the client would have asked for the latter name next.  At the moment, the hint data is left unpopulated, but we should be able to start populating it in the future without needing another protocol change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;deployment&quot;&gt;Deployment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electrum-NMC and upstream ElectrumX have both merged Protocol v1.4.3, so we’re now waiting for server operators to update.  Once we’ve determined that enough server operators have updated, we expect to flip a switch in the Electrum-NMC source code that enables the new protocol features.  This functionality should also work out of the box in other ElectrumX-supported coins that use a name index, which in practice means Xaya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s NGI0 Discovery Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2022/10/28/name-show-in-electrum-nmc-protocol-v1.4.3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2022/10/28/name-show-in-electrum-nmc-protocol-v1.4.3.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>winsvcwrap: Open source replacement for SRVANY in Golang</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike *nix platforms, system services on Windows must be specifically designed
to run as services, and written against the Win32 Service APIs. This creates a
problem when it is desired to run a program as a Windows system service which
was not designed to function in this role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SRVANY.EXE&lt;/code&gt; is an executable distributed by Microsoft in the Windows NT 4.0
Resource Kit, which can be used to adapt any program into a system service.
&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SRVANY.EXE&lt;/code&gt; is configured as the system service, and it spawns and supervises
the target process in turn. Thus, it forms an adapter between the Windows
service manager and arbitrary programs. However, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SRVANY&lt;/code&gt; is a proprietary
binary for which source code is not available, and is no longer even
distributed by Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/hlandau/winsvcwrap&quot;&gt;winsvcwrap&lt;/a&gt; is a simple open source Go
program to replace &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SRVANY&lt;/code&gt; and provide equivalent functionality, and is now
used by the Namecoin project to power its Windows installer bundle. This
enables the Namecoin project to avoid depending on an unmaintained proprietary
component. It can be used by anyone seeking to run arbitrary Windows programs
as Windows system services. Since it is written in Go, it is memory-safe
(unlike C/C++) and bootstrappable (unlike Rust).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by Cyphrs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2022/10/06/winsvcwrap-open-source-replacement-for-srvany.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2022/10/06/winsvcwrap-open-source-replacement-for-srvany.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Hugo Landau</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacktoberfest 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Namecoin is participating in &lt;a href=&quot;https://hacktoberfest.com/&quot;&gt;Hacktoberfest 2022&lt;/a&gt;.  If you’re interested in contributing to Namecoin, Hacktoberfest is a great chance to start (and maybe win a t-shirt).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/search?q=org%3Anamecoin+label%3Ahacktoberfest&amp;amp;state=open&amp;amp;type=Issues&quot;&gt;The list of Hacktoberfest issues for Namecoin is here.&lt;/a&gt;  Of course, we welcome other PR’s as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2022/10/05/hacktoberfest-2022.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2022/10/05/hacktoberfest-2022.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin Core 22.0 Released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Namecoin Core 22.0 has been released on the &lt;a href=&quot;/download/#namecoin-core-client-stable-release&quot;&gt;Downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what’s new since 0.21.0.1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RPC
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Deterministic salts.  (Reported by s7r; Design by Ryan Castellucci and Jeremy Rand; Patch by Yanmaani; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Transaction queue.  (Patch by Yanmaani; Review by Jeremy Rand and Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GUI
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;name_list&lt;/code&gt; Qt GUI.  (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Brandon Roberts, Randy Waterhouse, and Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;name_pending&lt;/code&gt; Qt GUI.  (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Edit contents of model instead of resetting.  (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;name_update&lt;/code&gt; Qt GUI.  (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Name renew Qt GUI.  (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft and Randy Waterhouse.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add Renew Names button.  (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fix double lock when creating a new wallet.  (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Name decoration in Qt GUI.  (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft and Brandon Roberts.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Misc
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fix name operations in descriptor wallets.  (Reported by Jeremy Rand; Patch by Daniel Kraft; Review by Jeremy Rand.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rebrand Cirrus build directory.  (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rebrand Guix.  (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add mainnet DNS seed from Jonas Ostman.  (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Update hardcoded seeds.  (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fix some AuxPoW CI errors.  (Reported by Jeremy Rand; Patch by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Numerous improvements from upstream Bitcoin Core.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2022/08/02/namecoin-core-22.0-released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2022/08/02/namecoin-core-22.0-released.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>Releases</category>
        
        <category>Namecoin Core Releases</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>pkcs11mod progress: Windows, macOS, certutil support, and more!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of things have been done with pkcs11mod since my &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/02/26/lab-leak-part-2-p11trustmod.html&quot;&gt;last post&lt;/a&gt; on the subject.  This is going to be a bit of a “grab bag” post without much structure (because that’s what reality looks like here, and this post is intended to reflect reality).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that the Chromium tests were hanging.  After a bit of investigation, I found that the flags I was passing to Chromium to make it run in Docker weren’t quite sufficient.  The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Zenika/alpine-chrome&quot;&gt;alpine-chrome&lt;/a&gt; project has a more thorough set of flags, and applying these to pkcs11mod’s test scripts got the tests passing again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I implemented the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GenerateKeyPair&lt;/code&gt; function in p11mod, which got the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;test-rsapub&lt;/code&gt; OpenDNSSEC test passing.  Thanks again to OpenDNSSEC for the test!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that trying to use either of the proxy modules with a nonexistent target module path resulted in a Go panic.  This is not good, since a panic will crash the host application.  Now this is mitigated by both pkcs11mod and p11mod checking for initialization errors, and returning &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CKR_GENERAL_ERROR&lt;/code&gt;, which is used by the PKCS#11 specification to indicate an error that is probably not recoverable.  The application can handle this however it likes, but whatever it does will probably be better than crashing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When trying to test pkcs11mod on Windows, I noticed that it failed very early.  So early that the Go runtime never even tried to initialize.  By comparing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pkcs11proxy.dll&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;nssckbi.dll&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://lucasg.github.io/Dependencies/&quot;&gt;Dependencies&lt;/a&gt;, I found that pkcs11mod was failing to export the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;C_GetFunctionList&lt;/code&gt; function, which caused applications to conclude that pkcs11proxy wasn’t a PKCS#11 module.  That explained the symptoms.  But wait, didn’t ncp11 work on Windows back when it was first released?  Yes.  Some digging found that this regression was caused by the fix for &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/golang/go/issues/30674&quot;&gt;Go issue 30674&lt;/a&gt;.  (Apparently, Go used to export all functions, and Windows has a tendency to crash if you export too many functions, so Go now requires developers to explicitly designate which functions will be exported.)  I fixed this via the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;__declspec(dllexport)&lt;/code&gt; attribute.  And now, pkcs11proxy is detected as a PKCS#11 module on Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I fixed the documentation (and Cirrus scripts) to generate libraries with the idiomatic &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pkcs11proxy.dll&lt;/code&gt; filename on Windows targets, instead of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;libpkcs11proxy.so&lt;/code&gt; filename that’s supposed to be only a Linux thing.  Not a big deal, but correct documentation is important.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added a trace mode (hidden behind an environment variable) to both pkcs11mod and p11mod, which makes it easier to follow what PKCS#11 calls are being issued.  Be warned, even running a proxy module for a minute or so can produce a trace log of over a megabyte, so this should not be done routinely.  Not all functions are traced yet; I’d happily accept PR’s to add more detailed tracing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added a test for &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/07/05/tstclnt-openssl-s_client-gnutls-cli-equivalent-for-nss.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tstclnt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on Debian, and noticed that it was failing.  Further investigation showed that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tstclnt&lt;/code&gt; was failing to read the trust bits from the CKBI module when &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;pkcs11proxy&lt;/code&gt; was in the middle.  This was odd, because I was already testing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tstclnt&lt;/code&gt; on Fedora, and it worked fine there.  The obvious difference was that Fedora uses Red Hat’s p11-kit CKBI module, while Debian uses Mozilla’s CKBI module.  Fedora’s replacement is &lt;em&gt;supposed&lt;/em&gt; to be compatible with Mozilla’s version, but clearly the Red Hat CKBI module was doing something different from Mozilla’s, and my code was expecting the behavior of Red Hat’s module.  Using the trace mode (see above paragraph), I figured out what was going on.  NSS queries for 4 different EKU trust attributes: TLS server authentication, TLS client authentication, email, and code signing.  (Clearly NSS could get away with only querying for TLS server authentication in this case, since &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tstclnt&lt;/code&gt; isn’t doing anything with the other three, but they don’t do that optimization here.  Which is probably okay, since most of the time, the extra queries won’t harm performace.)  Red Hat’s CKBI module contains trust bits for all 4 of those EKU attributes.  Mozilla’s CKBI module, however, omits the TLS client authentication attribute.  This makes sense, I guess, since the Mozila root CA program is not intended to be used for TLS client authentication, while Red Hat’s CKBI module incorporates certificates added by the user, which might be used for that EKU.  Here’s where the problem happens: NSS queries for all 4 trust attributes in a single &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GetAttributeValue&lt;/code&gt; function call.  Per the PKCS#11 specification, if any of the attributes in a oneshot query are missing, some extra error bits are returned, so that the caller knows which attributes existed and which didn’t.  However, Miek’s pkcs11 library doesn’t handle this case; it instead just returns an error, causing pkcs11mod to lose the trust bits attributes that did exist.  Patching Miek’s library seemed like an overkill approach, so I instead rigged pkcs11mod to detect the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CKR_ATTRIBUTE_SENSITIVE&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CKR_ATTRIBUTE_TYPE_INVALID&lt;/code&gt; error codes, and retry the attributes one at a time to figure out which ones we can return to the application.  This isn’t ideal performance-wise, since we end up retrieving the attributes twice, but the difference should be negligible in the real world.  And with that, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tstclnt&lt;/code&gt; on Debian passed the tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upstream p11 v1.1.0 added some named errors, which allowed me to avoid recognizing those errors via a brittle string comparison.  That makes my code cleaner, which is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added tests for Firefox and Chromium on Debian, which passed immediately (presumably because of the above &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;tstclnt&lt;/code&gt; fixes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I added tests for Firefox (both ESR and Nightly) on Windows.  These mostly passed, but I did need to fix the logfile output paths, since &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$HOME&lt;/code&gt; is not a thing on Windows.  The logfile is now saved to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;os.UserConfigDir()&lt;/code&gt;, which behaves sanely on all major OS’s.  It falls back to the current working directory if the user config directory isn’t accessible for some reason (e.g. sandboxing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then added some more Firefox variants on Windows: Firefox Rapid Release, Firefox Beta, Firefox Developer Edition, &lt;a href=&quot;https://librewolf.net/&quot;&gt;LibreWolf&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gnu.org/software/gnuzilla/&quot;&gt;GNU IceCat&lt;/a&gt;.  They all passed.  I also tried to add &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.waterfox.net/&quot;&gt;Waterfox&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.palemoon.org/&quot;&gt;Pale Moon&lt;/a&gt;, but Waterfox hung on the install step in my Cirrus VM, and Pale Moon doesn’t support the headless screenshot feature, which my tests rely on.  My guess is that both of them would work fine outside of my test environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, I added tests for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;certutil&lt;/code&gt; (the NSS tool, not the CryptoAPI tool of the same name).  Specifically, I dumped the CKBI certificate list, with trust bits, via pkcs11proxy and p11proxy, and compared the output to what I got without the proxy.  Surprisingly, this turned out to be a giant gopherhole [1].  Dumping the certificate list caused &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;certutil&lt;/code&gt; to segfault halfway through dumping when proxied – but only on Windows, and only via p11proxy (pkcs11proxy didn’t segfault).  Inspecting logs revealed that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;certutil&lt;/code&gt; was calling the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CloseAllSessions&lt;/code&gt; function, which &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;p11mod&lt;/code&gt; didn’t implement.  I implemented that function (it was pretty simple), but this didn’t fix the segfault.  I enabled the trace mode that I had previously added, and found that it was segfaulting after the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Finalize&lt;/code&gt; function had returned, which seemed odd, since that meant my code had already finished running by the point of the segfault.  After some confusion, I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/golang/go/issues/11100&quot;&gt;Go issue 11100&lt;/a&gt;, which described my problem: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;certutil&lt;/code&gt; had tried to unload &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;p11proxy.dll&lt;/code&gt;, which yanked some data structures out from under the Go runtime, causing a segfault.  There is a way to instruct Windows (via the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GET_MODULE_HANDLE_EX_FLAG_PIN&lt;/code&gt; argument to the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GetModuleHandleEx&lt;/code&gt; Windows API function) not to ever unload a DLL file until the application exits.  Conveniently, the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;golang.org/x/sys/windows&lt;/code&gt; package (nicknamed &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;goxsys/windows&lt;/code&gt; by the Tor folks [2]) has support for this.  I tried it out, and sure enough, that fixed the segfault.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this introduced a new issue.  Now, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;certutil&lt;/code&gt; wouldn’t segfault, but it would hang after outputting the entire certificate list, until I hit Ctrl-C in the command prompt.  Go issue 11100 had some mention of this occurring in Unity: apparently some applications wait for all background threads to exit before closing the program, and the Go runtime (which never terminates) is being recognized as such a background thread.  In theory, this is an application bug, but pkcs11proxy is supposed to leave the behavior of buggy software unchanged, so this was something I couldn’t just ignore.  Alas, I didn’t find a clean way to solve this.  So I did the dumb approach: when the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Finalize&lt;/code&gt; function is called, pkcs11mod starts a 5-second timer in a goroutine, which then calls &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;os.Exit(0)&lt;/code&gt;.  Sometimes the dumb approach is the best option that presents itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this meant that now, if an application tries to unload pkcs11mod, the application will be forcibly closed 5 seconds later.  This works fine for applications like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;certutil&lt;/code&gt; which will exit right after that point anyway.  But in Firefox, you probably don’t want your browser to kill itself 5 seconds after you click the Unload button in the Security Devices dialog.  So, what to do…?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/memes/one-does-not-simply-avoid-user-agent-sniffing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;One does not simply avoid user-agent sniffing.  Even in PKCS#11 modules.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yep, once again, sometimes the dumb approach is the best option that presents itself.  We simply check the process name that pkcs11mod is loaded into.  If it’s &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;certutil.exe&lt;/code&gt;, we start the 5-second exit timer; otherwise, we don’t.  The number of applications that exhibit this bug is, I’m guessing, small enough that we can simply enumerate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This got the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;certutil&lt;/code&gt; tests passing.  However, now the Firefox tests on Windows were failing.  Inspection of Firefox stderr indicated some error messages about a tab subprocess failing to start.  A DuckDuckGo search for these errors indicated a Bugzilla thread where the reporter said that disabling the Electrolysis sandbox fixed a crash.  I added some Cirrus tasks that ran my usual Firefox tests but with Electrolysis disabled.  Sure enough, those tests passed.  I initially figured that my usage of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;GetModuleHandleEx&lt;/code&gt;, or perhaps my attempt to read the process name, had violated some kind of sandbox policy, but after bisecting my recent changes, I came to a surprising conclusion: the thing that crashes Electrolysis is simply the act of &lt;em&gt;importing&lt;/em&gt; the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;goxsys/windows&lt;/code&gt; package.  I’m guessing there’s some kind of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;init()&lt;/code&gt; function inside that package that tries to do something that the sandbox doesn’t like, and panics when it gets a permission failure [3].  After grepping GitHub hoping someone had already found a solution to this, I discovered that the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/pipelined/vst2&quot;&gt;vst2&lt;/a&gt; project had already implemented a similar solution to mine, but using the lower-level &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;syscall&lt;/code&gt; package instead of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;goxsys/windows&lt;/code&gt;.  I copied their code nearly verbatim, and it worked out of the box: the DLL was pinned properly in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;certutil&lt;/code&gt;, and Electrolysis worked fine.  Thus bringing me out of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;certutil&lt;/code&gt; gopherhole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then relaxed a bit by adding macOS builds to Cirrus, and confirmed that pkcs11mod builds without errors on macOS.  (I don’t know if the binaries actually work, but they’re on Cirrus now, you can try them yourself and let me know.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, after discussion with the other pkcs11mod devs (Aerth and Bernard), we unanimously agreed to relicense pkcs11mod and ncp11 from LGPLv3+ to LGPLv2.1+.  This makes it unambiguously legal to use pkcs11mod with GPLv2-licensed applications.  The failure to do this initially was an oversight on our end; it was kind of ridiculous that we permitted pkcs11mod to be used with non-freedom software but not GPLv2 software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not yet at the point where I’d consider pkcs11mod to be well-tested enough to be used in production by people other than its 3 authors, but we are getting a lot closer to that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s Internet Hardening Fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&quot;https://go.dev/blog/gopher&quot;&gt;Rabbitholes are a thing in Plan 9, not Go.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] Insert Andrew “rasengan” Lee joke here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] The “goxfail” jokes write themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2022/06/13/pkcs11mod-windows-macos-certutil.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2022/06/13/pkcs11mod-windows-macos-certutil.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Electrum-NMC v4.0.0b1 fixes CVE-2022-31246</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Electrum-NMC v4.0.0b0 and earlier are affected by &lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2022-31246&quot;&gt;CVE-2022-31246&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/spesmilo/electrum/security/advisories/GHSA-4fh4-hx35-r355&quot;&gt;GHSA-4fh4-hx35-r355&lt;/a&gt; (the vulnerability is inherited from upstream Electrum).  Electrum-NMC v4.0.0b1 and ncdns for Windows v0.3.1 contain the fix.  Tor Browser Nightly was not vulnerable.  We would like to thank &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.unciphered.com/&quot;&gt;Unciphered&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://immunefi.com/&quot;&gt;Immunefi&lt;/a&gt; for reporting the vulnerability and coordinating the disclosure with us, and upstream Electrum for implementing the fix.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2022/06/08/electrum-nmc-cve-2022-31246.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2022/06/08/electrum-nmc-cve-2022-31246.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>Alerts</category>
        
        <category>Electrum-NMC Alerts</category>
        
        <category>ncdns Alerts</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ncdns v0.3.1 Released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve released ncdns v0.3.1.  This Windows-only release includes important improvements to memory safety and UX; we recommend that all Windows users upgrade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full changelog of what’s new since v0.3:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;certinject
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Code quality improvements.  Patches by Jeremy Rand.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ncdns
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Code quality improvements.  Patches by Jeremy Rand.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ncprop279
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fix stderr privacy leak when tlshook is enabled at compile-time.  Patch by Jeremy Rand.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Code quality improvements.  Patches by Jeremy Rand.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;StemNS
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Log errors to stderr. Patch by Jeremy Rand.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Redact target address from stderr logs.  Patch by Jeremy Rand.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Load configuration from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;config&lt;/code&gt; folder.  Reported by Patrick Schleizer; patch by Yanmaani.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Support &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ControlPort auto&lt;/code&gt;.  Reported by Adolf-Putin-2022; patch by Jeremy Rand.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Code quality improvements.  Patches by Jeremy Rand.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;x509-compressed
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fix Go 1.18.x compatibility.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Windows installer
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Switch from BIND’s dnssec-keygen to CoreDNS’s coredns-keygen.  Unlike BIND, CoreDNS is memory-safe and has no non-freedom build dependencies.  This also means the Visual C++ Runtime is no longer required.  Reported by Yana Timoshenko and Aminda Suomalainen; patch by Jeremy Rand.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fix compatibility with StemNS’s conf.d feature.  Patch by Jeremy Rand.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Log StemNS stderr to event log.  Makes it easier to diagnose Tor Browser configuration bugs.  Patch by Jeremy Rand.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Work around PowerShell v2 bug.  Partially fixes Windows 7 compatibility.  Reported by Cyphrs; patch by Jeremy Rand.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Code quality improvements.  Patches by Jeremy Rand.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Build system
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bump Electrum-NMC to v4.0.0b1.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bump godns to v1.1.49.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Bump tor-browser-build to v11.5a12.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, you can download it at the &lt;a href=&quot;/download/#ncdns&quot;&gt;Downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by Cyphrs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.namecoin.org/2022/06/04/ncdns-v0.3.1-released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.namecoin.org/2022/06/04/ncdns-v0.3.1-released.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>Releases</category>
        
        <category>ncdns Releases</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
