<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Namecoin</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>https://namecoin.org//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://namecoin.org//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 22:49:40 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 22:49:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Video, Slides, and Paper from Namecoin at GCER 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As was &lt;a href=&quot;/2017/07/06/gcer-2017.html&quot;&gt;announced&lt;/a&gt;, I represented Namecoin at the 2017 Global Conference on Educational Robotics.  Although GCER doesn’t produce official recordings of their talks, I was able to obtain an amateur recording of my talk from an audience member.  I’ve also posted my slides, as well as my paper from the conference proceedings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that, as this is an amateur recording, the audio quality is not spectacular.  It should also be noted that the audience is rather different from the audiences for whom I usually give Namecoin talks; as a result, the focus of the content is also rather different from my usual Namecoin talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.namecoin.org/files/videos/gcer-2017/Namecoin-GCER-2017-1080p.webm&quot;&gt;The WebM amateur video recording of my talk is here (hosted by Namecoin.org).&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/resources/presentations/GCER_2017/Namecoin_GCER_2017_Slides.pdf&quot;&gt;My slides are available here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/resources/presentations/GCER_2017/Namecoin_GCER_2017_Paper.pdf&quot;&gt;My paper is available here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to the staff and volunteers from KISS Institute for Practical Robotics, who organized GCER.  Especially big thanks to Roger Clement and Steve Goodgame for giving me excellent feedback on the general outline of my paper and talk.  This was an excellent event, and I look forward to the next time I’m able to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.org//2017/08/31/gcer-2017-video.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.org//2017/08/31/gcer-2017-video.html</guid>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ncdns v0.0.4 Released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve released ncdns v0.0.4.  This release incorporates a bugfix in the madns dependency, which fixes a DNSSEC signing bug.  The ncdns Windows installer in this release also updated the Dnssec-Trigger dependency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, you can download it at the &lt;a href=&quot;/download/betas/&quot;&gt;Beta Downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s Internet Hardening Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.org//2017/08/24/ncdns-v0.0.4-released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.org//2017/08/24/ncdns-v0.0.4-released.html</guid>
        
        <category>Releases</category>
        
        <category>ncdns Releases</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TLS Support for Chromium on Windows Released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After quite a bit of code cleanup, we’ve released a new beta of ncdns for Windows, which includes Namecoin-based TLS certificate validation for Chromium, Google Chrome, and Opera on Windows.  This includes both the CryptoAPI certificate injection and NUMS HPKP injection that were discussed previously.  You can download it on the &lt;a href=&quot;/download/betas/&quot;&gt;Beta Downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.  We’ve also posted binaries of ncdns (without install scripts or TLS support) for a number of other operating systems; they’re also linked on the Beta Downloads page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Credit for this release goes to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeremy Rand: Cert injection Go implementation; NUMS HPKP injection concept and Go implementation; review of Hugo’s code.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hugo Landau: Cert injection NSIS implementation; NUMS HPKP injection NSIS implementation; review of Jeremy’s code.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ryan Castellucci: Dehydrated certificates concept+algorithm; NUMS hash algorithm and Python implementation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s Internet Hardening Fund.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Namecoin TLS development focus has started to shift toward Firefox TLS support.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.org//2017/08/03/tls-for-chromium-windows-released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.org//2017/08/03/tls-for-chromium-windows-released.html</guid>
        
        <category>Releases</category>
        
        <category>ncdns Releases</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>QCon London 2017 Video: Case Study: Alternate Blockchains</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;InfoQ has posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infoq.com/presentations/namecoin-monero&quot;&gt;the recording of my talk, Case Study: Alternate Blockchains&lt;/a&gt; at QCon London 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The videos on the InfoQ website do not appear to work when Javascript is disabled.  Security-conscious users who prefer not to enable Javascript can view the video via &lt;a href=&quot;https://rg3.github.io/youtube-dl/&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://packages.debian.org/stretch/youtube-dl&quot;&gt;Debian package&lt;/a&gt;) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.whonix.org/t/vlc-apparmor-profile-wip-streaming-documentation-for-whonix-install-youtube-dl-by-default/2918&quot;&gt;recommendation by Whonix&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/resources/presentations/QCon_London_2017/Namecoin_QCon_London_2017.pdf&quot;&gt;My slides are available here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.org//2017/07/28/qcon-london-case-study-video.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.org//2017/07/28/qcon-london-case-study-video.html</guid>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>LibreTorNS Merged to Upstream TorNS</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Generally I’m of the opinion that it’s better to get patches to other people’s projects merged upstream whenever feasible; accordingly I submitted the LibreTorNS patches upstream.  Happily, meejah has merged the LibreTorNS patches to &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/meejah/torns&quot;&gt;upstream TorNS&lt;/a&gt;.  That means LibreTorNS is now obsolete, and you should use meejah’s upstream TorNS for testing dns-prop279 going forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to meejah for accepting the patch!  Also thanks to meejah for the code review – there was a bug hiding in my initial submitted patch, which is one of the reasons I always prefer getting things reviewed by upstream.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.org//2017/07/07/libretorns-merged-upstream.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.org//2017/07/07/libretorns-merged-upstream.html</guid>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin&#39;s Jeremy Rand will be a speaker at GCER 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I will be speaking at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://new.gcer.net/&quot;&gt;2017 Global Conference on Educational Robotics&lt;/a&gt; (July 8-12, 2017).  For those of you unfamiliar with GCER, the audience is mostly a mix of middle school students, high school students, college students, and educators, most of whom are participating in the robotics competitions hosted at GCER (primarily Botball).  I competed in Botball (and the other 2 GCER competitions: KIPR Open and KIPR Aerial) between 2003 and 2015, and that experience (particularly the hacking aspect, which is actively encouraged in all three competitions) was a major factor in why I’m a Namecoin developer.  My talk is an outreach effort, which I hope will result in increased interest in the Botball scene in the areas of privacy, security, and human rights.  My talk (scheduled for July 10) is entitled “Making HTTPS and Anonymity Networks Slightly More Secure (Or: How I’m Using My Botball Skill Set in the Privacy/Security Field)”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to KISS Institute for Practical Robotics (which organizes GCER) for suggesting that I give this talk.  Looking forward to it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.org//2017/07/06/gcer-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.org//2017/07/06/gcer-2017.html</guid>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>QCon London 2017 Video: Practical Cryptography &amp; Blockchain Panel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;InfoQ has posted &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.infoq.com/presentations/cryptography-blockchain&quot;&gt;the recording of the Practical Cryptography &amp;amp; Blockchain Panel&lt;/a&gt; at QCon London 2017.  The panelists (from left to right) were Elaine Ou, me (Jeremy Rand), David Vorick, Paul Sztorc, and Peter Todd.  Riccardo Spagni (on the right) moderated the panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The videos on the InfoQ website do not appear to work when Javascript is disabled.  Security-conscious users who prefer not to enable Javascript can view the video via &lt;a href=&quot;https://rg3.github.io/youtube-dl/&quot;&gt;youtube-dl&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;https://packages.debian.org/stretch/youtube-dl&quot;&gt;Debian package&lt;/a&gt;) (&lt;a href=&quot;https://forums.whonix.org/t/vlc-apparmor-profile-wip-streaming-documentation-for-whonix-install-youtube-dl-by-default/2918&quot;&gt;recommendation by Whonix&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.org//2017/07/05/qcon-london-panel-video.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.org//2017/07/05/qcon-london-panel-video.html</guid>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin Resolution for Tor Released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;/2017/06/21/tor-prop279.html&quot;&gt;aforementioned licensing issues with TorNS&lt;/a&gt; have been dealt with, and I’ve released the DNS provider for Tor’s Prop279 Pluggable Naming API.  This allows Namecoin resolution in Tor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One issue I encountered is that TorNS currently implements a rather unfortunate restriction that input and output domain names must be in the &lt;code&gt;.onion&lt;/code&gt; TLD.  I’ve created a fork of TorNS (which I call &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/namecoin/LibreTorNS&quot;&gt;LibreTorNS&lt;/a&gt;) which removes this restriction.  LibreTorNS is currently required for Namecoin usage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;/download/betas/&quot;&gt;Beta Downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.  Please let me know what works and what doesn’t.  And remember, using Namecoin naming with Tor will make you heavily stand out, so don’t use this in any scenario where you need anonymity.  (Also please refer to the extensive additional scary warnings in the readme if you’re under the mistaken impression that using this in production is a good idea.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This development was funded by NLnet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.org//2017/06/22/tor-prop279-release.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.org//2017/06/22/tor-prop279-release.html</guid>
        
        <category>Releases</category>
        
        <category>Prop279 Releases</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin Resolution for Tor (DNS Provider for Tor Prop279 Pluggable Naming API)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A while back, I &lt;a href=&quot;https://lists.torproject.org/pipermail/tor-dev/2017-April/012222.html&quot;&gt;released on the tor-dev mailing list&lt;/a&gt; a tool for using Namecoin naming with Tor.  It worked, but it was clearly a proof of concept.  For example, it didn’t implement most of the Namecoin domain names spec, it didn’t work with the libdohj client, and it used the Tor controller API.  I’ve now coded a new tool that fixes these issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fixing the spec compliance and libdohj compatibility was implemented by using ncdns as a backend instead of directly talking to Namecoin Core.  Interestingly, I decided not to do anything Namecoin-specific with this tool.  It simply uses the DNS protocol to talk to ncdns, or any other DNS server you provide.  (So yes, that means that you could, in theory, use the DNS instead of Namecoin, without modifying this tool at all.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to work with the DNS protocol, some changes were made to how &lt;code&gt;.onion&lt;/code&gt; domains are stored in Namecoin.  The existing convention is to use the &lt;code&gt;tor&lt;/code&gt; field of a domain, which has no DNS mapping.  Instead, I’m using the &lt;code&gt;txt&lt;/code&gt; field of the &lt;code&gt;_tor&lt;/code&gt; subdomain of a domain.  This is consistent with existing practice in the DNS world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tool is using Tor’s Prop279 Pluggable Naming protocol rather than the Tor controller API.  Right now &lt;code&gt;tor&lt;/code&gt; (little-t) doesn’t implement Prop279.  To experiment with Prop279, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/meejah/torns&quot;&gt;TorNS&lt;/a&gt; is a useful way of simulating Prop279 support using the control port as a backend.  Unfortunately, TorNS’s license is unclear at the moment.  I’m in the process of checking with meejah (author of TorNS) to see if TorNS can be released under a free software license.  Until that minor bit of legalese is taken care of, the release of Namecoin resolution for Tor is on hold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This development was funded by NLnet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.org//2017/06/21/tor-prop279.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.org//2017/06/21/tor-prop279.html</guid>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Automated Nothing-Up-My-Sleeve HPKP Insertion for Chromium</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned in &lt;a href=&quot;/2017/06/15/how-were-doing-tls-for-chromium.html&quot;&gt;my previous post&lt;/a&gt;, we protect from compromised CA’s by using a nothing-up-my-sleeve (NUMS) HPKP pin in Chromium.  Previously, it was necessary for the user to add this pin themselves in the Chromium UI.  This was really sketchy from both a security and UX point of view.  I have now submitted a PR to ncdns that will automatically add the necessary pin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is implemented as a standalone program that is intended to be run at install.  It works by parsing Chromium’s &lt;code&gt;TransportSecurity&lt;/code&gt; storage file (which is just JSON), adding an entry for &lt;code&gt;bit&lt;/code&gt; that contains the NUMS key pin, and then saving the result as JSON back to &lt;code&gt;TransportSecurity&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I expect this to work for most browsers based on Chromium (e.g. Chrome and Opera), on most OS’s (e.g. GNU/Linux, Windows, and macOS), but so far I’ve only tested with Chrome on Windows.  I don’t expect it to work with Electron-based applications such as Riot and Brave; Electron doesn’t seem to follow the standard Chromium conventions on HPKP.  I haven’t yet examined Electron to see if there’s a way we can get it to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn’t yet integrated with the NSIS installer; I’ll be asking Hugo to take a look at doing the integration there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.org//2017/06/20/automated-nums-hpkp.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.org//2017/06/20/automated-nums-hpkp.html</guid>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
