<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Namecoin</title>
    <description><!--Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
--></description>
    <link>https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en</language>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 14:08:30 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 14:08:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/images/logo.png</url>
      <title>Namecoin</title>
      <link>https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/</link>
      <width>134</width>
      <height>25</height>
    </image>
    
      <item>
        <title>Enhancing Proxy Leak Detection with SocksTrace: From ptrace to seccomp notify</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Initially, SocksTrace relied on &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ptrace&lt;/code&gt; to trace connect syscalls. While &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ptrace&lt;/code&gt; works well for simple programs, it wasn’t practical for high-performance applications, especially browsers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-switch-to-seccomp-notify&quot;&gt;Why switch to seccomp notify?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Performance: ptrace slowed down applications significantly, making it impractical for real-time proxy leak detection.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scalability: Large, multithreaded programs like browsers were difficult to trace effectively using ptrace.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More precise control: seccomp notify allows SocksTrace to intercept only the syscalls it cares about, without stepping through every syscall like ptrace does.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-the-transition-works&quot;&gt;How the transition works&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;PTRACE_SYSCALL&lt;/code&gt; to catch connect, SocksTrace now sets up a seccomp filter with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;SECCOMP_RET_USER_NOTIF&lt;/code&gt;. This allows user-space handling of specific syscalls, without the overhead of stepping through every process instruction. When connect is intercepted, SocksTrace can inspect the syscall parameters, decide whether to allow or deny it, and act accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whitelisting-syscalls&quot;&gt;Whitelisting syscalls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;seccomp&lt;/code&gt;, SocksTrace can define a strict policy that only allows necessary syscalls, blocking everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-syscall-whitelisting-matters&quot;&gt;Why syscall whitelisting matters&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reduces the attack surface by preventing unnecessary syscalls.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensures SocksTrace only intercepts network-related calls without interfering with other system behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Can be extended for different security policies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;implementation-details&quot;&gt;Implementation details&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;go-seccomp-bpf&lt;/code&gt;, SocksTrace creates a seccomp filter that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blocks all syscalls by default (ActionErrno).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explicitly allows safe syscalls like read, write and exit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uses &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;seccomp.ActionTrace&lt;/code&gt; to intercept connect for analysis.
This prevents unauthorized connections while ensuring minimal disruption to the application’s normal behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;configuring-tcp-blocking&quot;&gt;Configuring TCP blocking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new feature in SocksTrace allows users to decide whether to block incoming TCP connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-does-it-work&quot;&gt;How does it work?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By intercepting &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bind&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;accept&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;accept4&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;listen&lt;/code&gt;, SocksTrace can monitor and control incoming TCP connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;configurable-blocking-options&quot;&gt;Configurable blocking options&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, SocksTrace offers two options for incoming TCP connections:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allow all incoming connections.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Block all incoming connections (to prevent accidental exposure).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are also working on an option to allow only specific addresses, adding more fine-grained control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s Next Generation Internet Zero Core Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2025/03/30/sockstrace-seccomp-notify.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2025/03/30/sockstrace-seccomp-notify.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin Receives TLS and Anonymity Research Funding from Power Up Privacy and NLnet Foundation’s NGI0 Core Fund</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re happy to announce that Namecoin is receiving three new grants:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$25,760 USD from Power Up Privacy for anonymity research and development.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Alice Margatroid is project lead.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Jeremy Rand and Brandon Roberts will assist as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;$24,480 USD from Power Up Privacy for TLS research and development.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Jeremy Rand is project lead.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Robert Nganga will assist as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;20,000 EUR from NLnet Foundation’s NGI0 Core (Next Generation Internet: Zero Core) Fund for TLS research and development.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Jeremy Rand is project lead.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Robert Nganga will assist as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;anonymity-rd-grant&quot;&gt;Anonymity R&amp;amp;D Grant&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most anonymity-related tools focus on preventing metadata leaks, e.g. Tor (prevents leaking your IP address metadata) and Mullvad Browser (prevents leaking your browser fingerprint metadata). However, there is another class of deanonymization vectors: the content of the communication itself. For example, mentioning the weather is an easy way to severely narrow your anonymity set. Alice is developing an automated tool that warns users if they are at risk of deanonymizing themselves in this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Namecoin has a solid history of developing privacy/security tools that aren’t strictly tied to the Namecoin blockchain, including SocksTrace, certinject, and pkcs11mod. This isn’t unusual in this space; Tor Project also routinely publishes research that isn’t strictly related to the Tor network. We’re excited to continue this trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tls-rd-grants&quot;&gt;TLS R&amp;amp;D Grants&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Namecoin’s TLS support has a solid track record on scalability, including our innovations on layer-2 TLS. These grants will cover additional Namecoin scalability improvements, including fleshing out various functionality that Robert’s 38C3 talk covered. They will also cover collaboration with Tor Project on areas of TLS-related common interest, including fleshing out the onion service functionality that Jeremy’s 38C3 talk covered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our collaboration with Tor Project goes back many years, and we’re happy that this will be continuing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;funding-sources&quot;&gt;Funding Sources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re probably familiar with NLnet Foundation by now, but if not, you might want to read &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnet.nl/foundation/&quot;&gt;about NLnet Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, or just take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnet.nl/thema/index.html&quot;&gt;the projects they’ve funded over the years&lt;/a&gt; (you might see some familiar names).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://powerupprivacy.com/&quot;&gt;Power Up Privacy&lt;/a&gt; is a relatively new funder whom you may not have heard of, but they fund some familar names as well. Diversifying Namecoin’s funding has been a goal for a while now, and we’re pleased to add Power Up Privacy to our growing list of funders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank the awesome people at NLnet Foundation for the continued vote of confidence, as well as the European Commision for their support of the Next Generation Internet. And a huge thank-you to Power Up Privacy for their new support!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alice and Jeremy will be posting updates regularly as development proceeds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2025/03/30/namecoin-tls-anonymity-research-funding-power-up-privacy-nlnet-ngi0-core.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2025/03/30/namecoin-tls-anonymity-research-funding-power-up-privacy-nlnet-ngi0-core.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Alice Margatroid and Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>38C3 Summary</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As was &lt;a href=&quot;/2024/12/16/38c3-fosdem-2025.html&quot;&gt;previously announced&lt;/a&gt;, several developers represented Namecoin at &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.ccc.de/congress/2024/wiki/index.php/Main_Page&quot;&gt;38C3&lt;/a&gt; in Leipzig, Germany. You know the drill by now: we had a lot of conversations with other attendees, and we won’t be publicly disclosing the content of those conversations, because I want people to be able to talk to us at conferences without worrying that off-the-cuff comments will be broadcast to the public. That said, a practical result of one of those conversations should be getting its own announcement in the next day or two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were multiple Namecoin-related talks at the Critical Decentralization Cluster (CDC). We’re still waiting for the official recordings to be published, but in the meantime, live-stream archives are provided below where available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lightning-talk-intro-to-namecoin&quot;&gt;Lightning Talk: Intro to Namecoin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Yanmaani&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pretalx.riat.at/38c3/talk/PQRLPH/&quot;&gt;Pretalx page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Was not live-streamed; recording coming soon.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lightning-talk-intro-to-sibermerdeka&quot;&gt;Lightning Talk: Intro to Sibermerdeka&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Rose Turing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pretalx.riat.at/38c3/talk/PQRLPH/&quot;&gt;Pretalx page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Was not live-streamed; recording coming soon.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-lost-art-forgotten-primitives-for-a-decentralized-web&quot;&gt;A lost art: forgotten primitives for a decentralized web&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Yanmaani&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There were many projects around the new millennium seeking to create decentralized/anonymous networks. Most failed, but they had some good ideas that died along with them. This talk will cover some “lost gems” from that era.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most development within anonymous overlay networks the past 20 years has centered around low-latency networks (like Tor or I2P); networks that allow you to use conventional web applications and protocols. (like IRC, or whatever web applications you want)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High-latency networks don’t allow you to do this. They require you to re-build everything from the ground up. That’s why they never took off, but it also required clever people to spend a lot of time building interesting things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This short talk will cover the primitives that were used to build things like decentralized web sites, search engines, identity systems, and even bulletin boards. While of little practical use today, the techniques in some ways exceed our current technology and ought to be remembered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pretalx.riat.at/38c3/talk/D8YKHW/&quot;&gt;Pretalx page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Was not live-streamed; recording coming soon.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;not-your-keys-not-your-name&quot;&gt;Not Your Keys, Not Your Name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Adam Joseph&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This talk will explain the benefits of decentralized protocols which use public keys &lt;em&gt;directly&lt;/em&gt; as identities, and encourage this approach for newly-designed protocols.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The example familiar to the most CCC attendees is Tor &lt;a href=&quot;http://2gzyxa5ihm7nsggfxnu52rck2vv4rvmdlkiu3zzui5du4xyclen53wid.onion/&quot;&gt;onion names&lt;/a&gt;. At least &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeberg.org/amjoseph/not-your-keys-not-your-name&quot;&gt;20 other protocols use this strategy&lt;/a&gt; as well. This talk will briefly survey those examples and explain the benefits of this approach for &lt;em&gt;autonomy&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;decentralization&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;ability to resist surveillance&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main alternative to public keys is names controlled by some globally trusted party, such as US-ICANN, the DNSSEC root key, or the browser-vendors’ WebPKI appointees. This talk will explain the drawbacks of centralized alternatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If a protocol uses public keys as identities, it should allow users to keep their permanent private key offline. Private keys in &lt;em&gt;online&lt;/em&gt; “secure elements” are not offline. Because an online device requires a network connection its physical location cannot be hidden; this means it can be seized or stolen and the keys extracted using a vulnerability like &lt;a href=&quot;https://eprint.iacr.org/2024/1380&quot;&gt;the one recently discovered in all Yubikeys and Infineon TPMs&lt;/a&gt;. Only a small number of protocols support offline identity keys. This support cannot be added to a protocol “after the fact”; it must be included from the very beginning. This talk will encourage protocol designers to include this feature from the very beginning, and will give concrete advice (“copy SSH or Tor”) on how to do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details can be found here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeberg.org/amjoseph/not-your-keys-not-your-name&quot;&gt;https://codeberg.org/amjoseph/not-your-keys-not-your-name&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pretalx.riat.at/38c3/talk/8FCVKL/&quot;&gt;Pretalx page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/live/JPK7J9FVdvo?feature=shared&amp;amp;t=1730&quot;&gt;Live-stream archive on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-authenticating-tls-certificates-for-tor-onion-services&quot;&gt;Self-Authenticating TLS Certificates for Tor Onion Services&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jeremy Rand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLS (the security layer behind HTTPS) and Tor onion services (anonymously hosted TCP services) are both excellent protocols. Wouldn’t it be nice if we could use them together? In this talk, I’ll cover a working implementation of combining TLS with onion services, without compromising on the security properties that each provides.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topics to be covered include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why would you want to combine TLS with onion services? Why isn’t onion service encryption good enough?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why isn’t unauthenticated TLS (e.g. self-signed certificates) good enough for onion services?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can we authenticate a TLS certificate for a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.onion&lt;/code&gt; domain without relying on public CA’s like Let’s Encrypt or any other trusted third parties? (No we’re not using a blockchain.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can we teach standard (unmodified) web browsers like Firefox to apply different certificate validation logic for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.onion&lt;/code&gt; certificates?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can we teach standard (unmodified) web browsers like Firefox to validate certificates using typically-unsupported elliptic curves like Ed25519 (which Tor uses)?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How is teaching standard (unmodified) web browsers like Firefox to validate &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.onion&lt;/code&gt; certificates similar to Namecoin &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.bit&lt;/code&gt; certificates? How is it different?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pretalx.riat.at/38c3/talk/QT333R/&quot;&gt;Pretalx page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/live/JPK7J9FVdvo?feature=shared&amp;amp;t=5378&quot;&gt;Live-stream archive on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scaling-namecoin&quot;&gt;Scaling Namecoin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Robert Nganga&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The DNS has an inherent scalability advantage over Namecoin. But that doesn’t mean we’re not going to optimize Namecoin as best we can. In this talk, I’ll cover several tactics we’re using to reduce the on-chain data stored by Namecoin — while minimizing the UX impact.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topics to be covered include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why is the Namecoin value size only 520 bytes?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can security improvements like cold storage support allow storing more data?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How did we avoid putting TLS public keys in the blockchain?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How are we compressing the data that goes into the blockchain?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How are we shrinking the on-chain overhead of registrations of new names?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There may be bit of bonus content covering other Namecoin development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pretalx.riat.at/38c3/talk/8YWD9D/&quot;&gt;Pretalx page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/live/JPK7J9FVdvo?feature=shared&amp;amp;t=7088&quot;&gt;Live-stream archive on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;protecting-namecoin-users-from-their-mistakes-namecoin-wallet-ux&quot;&gt;Protecting Namecoin Users from Their Mistakes: Namecoin Wallet UX&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Rose Turing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If user mistakes cause their website to go down, that’s already bad — but not nearly as bad as if user mistakes make them permanently lose control of their website or get doxed and arrested. This talk is about how we’re helping Namecoin wallet users avoid mistakes before they cause irreversible consequences.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are generally way more careless than we give them credit for, and all it takes for a full on security breach is one mistake, anywhere in the worst of cases. Our job in Namecoin is to prevent such incidents from occurring, and this means designing our UX in such a way that mistakes can be avoided by end-users. In this talk we discuss the consequences of mistakes on the user’s end as well as mitigations that have or will be implemented in Namecoin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topics to be covered include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Warning about likely-invalid domain configurations.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Preventing accidental expiration disasters.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://pretalx.riat.at/38c3/talk/7TNDME/&quot;&gt;Pretalx page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/live/JPK7J9FVdvo?feature=shared&amp;amp;t=8129&quot;&gt;Live-stream archive on YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge thank you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://decentral.community/&quot;&gt;The Critical Decentralization Cluster&lt;/a&gt; for facilitating our participation. We’re looking forward to 39C3 in December 2025!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s Internet Hardening Fund, NLnet Foundation’s Next Generation Internet Zero Core Fund, and Cyphrs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2025/03/30/38c3-summary.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2025/03/30/38c3-summary.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin will be at 38C3 and FOSDEM 2025</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re happy to announce that at least three Namecoin developers will be at &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.ccc.de/congress/2024/wiki/index.php/Main_Page&quot;&gt;38C3 (the 38th Chaos Communication Congress)&lt;/a&gt; in Hamburg, December 27-30. Additionally, at least two Namecoin developers will be at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fosdem.org/2025/&quot;&gt;FOSDEM 2025&lt;/a&gt; in Brussels, February 1-2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect to give some talks, however, the details are still in flux and will probably not be announced until shortly before the beginning of the respective conferences; keep an eye on both the C3 and FOSDEM schedules to find us (or find our absence, if we are unlucky). Recordings and live-streams may happen as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may recall, last year’s Congress (37C3) was the first year that Namecoin stepped out from Monero’s shadow to form our own Assembly. This was a huge success for all involved, and the Namecoin Assembly is back this year. Of course, we remain close friends with Monero. Meanwhile this will be our first time attending FOSDEM, so we’re very excited to see what we’ve been missing all these years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to meet up with us at C3, the usual methods (c3nav, etc) should lead you to us. Meanwhile if you’d like to meet up with us at FOSDEM, you can say hello in the #namecoin-dev Matrix channel, or you can ask at the NLnet table and perhaps they may be able to point you in our direction.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/12/16/38c3-fosdem-2025.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/12/16/38c3-fosdem-2025.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin Core 28.0 (Almost) Released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Namecoin Core 28.0 has been released on the &lt;a href=&quot;/download/betas/#namecoin-core&quot;&gt;Beta Downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s what’s new since 22.0:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;RPC
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Disambiguate “expired” from “never existed” in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;name_show&lt;/code&gt; error message. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GUI
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Disable configuring/renewing names that are unspendable due to expiration or transfer. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Clarify passphrase dialog to make clear that names are protected by the passphrase. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Clarify Receive tab to make clear that it can be used for name transfers. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fix suboptimal Unicode usage in Manage Names tab. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add “Export” button to Manage Names tab. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;name_firstupdate&lt;/code&gt; Qt GUI. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add decoration for incoming and outgoing name transfers. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add decoration for name renewals. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Move name operation into Type column. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add icon for Configure Name button. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Show name count in Manage Names tab. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check availability in Buy Names tab. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Show &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;.bit&lt;/code&gt; form for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;d/&lt;/code&gt; names in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TransactionRecord&lt;/code&gt;. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Show namespace in Type column of Transactions tab. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft and Yanmaani.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Prioritize Data over Transfer in tab order in Configure Name dialog. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Avoid jargon in Configure Name dialog. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Show value size in Configure Name dialog. (Patch by Jeremy Rand; Review by Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check for invalid JSON in Configure Name dialog. (Patch by Rose Turing; Review by Jeremy Rand and Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Check for non-minimal JSON in Configure Name dialog. (Patch by Rose Turing; Review by Jeremy Rand and Daniel Kraft.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Misc
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;fundrawtransaction&lt;/code&gt; more in the suggested atomic name trades workflow. (Patch by Daniel Kraft; Review by Yanmaani.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Add mainnet DNS seeds from s7r. (Patch by s7r; Review by Daniel Kraft and Jeremy Rand.)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Fix missing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#include&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;buynamespage.h&lt;/code&gt;. (Patch by Zoltan Konder; Review by Daniel Kraft and Jeremy Rand.)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Numerous improvements from upstream Bitcoin Core.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Known potential issues (will hopefully be resolved soon):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initial peer discovery may not work reliably over Tor.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setting &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-fallbackfee&lt;/code&gt; may be needed if you don’t want to wait some blocks before you can issue transactions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Buy Names tab only performs &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;name_firstupdate&lt;/code&gt;, not &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;name_new&lt;/code&gt;; you’ll have to do &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;name_new&lt;/code&gt; from the console first.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Buy Names tab might require setting &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-addresstype bech32 -changetype bech32&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Some GUI lag is present when switching to the Overview and Transactions tabs, and when scrolling in the Transactions tab.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Old BDB-based wallets are no longer supported (per upstream policy). Migration of BDB wallets to the new Descriptor wallets is not thoroughly tested, so if you have high-value BDB wallets, you may want to back them up and keep an old version of Namecoin Core around until you are confident that your wallets migrated properly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is it on the Beta Downloads page, you ask? As of this writing, we only have 1 set of Guix signatures, and we require 2 sets to do a release. For logistical optimization reasons, we have decided to upload the binaries and publish the changelog now. However, do not consider the release to be official until a 2nd set of matching Guix signatures has had a PR submitted (which we expect to be in the next week). We fully expect these binaries to be bit-for-bit identical to the ones that we place on the main Downloads page in a little while. If you see another set of matching Guix signatures by the time you read this, then you can safely conclude that these binaries are of the quality you would normally expect on the main Downloads page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to Rose Turing for Guix-signing this release. Also huge pre-emptive thanks to Robert Nganga for Guix-signing this release in the next week or so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by Cyphrs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/12/15/namecoin-core-28.0-released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/12/15/namecoin-core-28.0-released.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>Releases</category>
        
        <category>Namecoin Core Releases</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin's SocksTrace Receives Funding from NLnet Foundation’s NGI0 Core Fund</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re happy to announce that Namecoin is &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnet.nl/news/2024/20241003-announcing-Core-call.html&quot;&gt;receiving&lt;/a&gt; additional funding from NLnet Foundation’s NGI0 Core (Next Generation Internet: Zero Core) Fund. If you’re unfamiliar with NLnet, you might want to read &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnet.nl/foundation/&quot;&gt;about NLnet Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, or just take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnet.nl/thema/index.html&quot;&gt;the projects they’ve funded over the years&lt;/a&gt; (you might see some familiar names).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new funding is focused on SocksTrace. You might know SocksTrace by its former (and truly magical) name, Heteronculous-Horklump. While the former name was hilarious for Harry Potter geeks, we got feedback at 37C3 that it was too… let’s say, “unmemorable” for the rest of the world (especially for non-native English speakers); thus, we’ve seized the chance to simplify things with a name that’s easier on the brain. Don’t worry, though—the new name is still meme-worthy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SocksTrace is a proxy leak detection tool designed for both CI testing and manual QA testing. It leverages the Linux &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ptrace&lt;/code&gt; feature to monitor socket syscalls that could potentially bypass a proxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the following areas of development will be funded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved speed by whitelisting specific syscalls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Handling incoming TCP (Transmission Control Protocol) connections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved test coverage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enforce stream isolation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide support for POWER systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SOCKSify DNS traffic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work will principally be done by developers Jeremy Rand and Robert Nganga (who is the author of this post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank the awesome people at NLnet Foundation for the continued vote of confidence, as well as the European Commision for their support of the Next Generation Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be posting updates regularly as development proceeds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/10/21/sockstrace-funding-nlnet-ngi0-core.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/10/21/sockstrace-funding-nlnet-ngi0-core.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Meeting 2024 / GPN 22 / MoneroKon 4 Summary (UPDATED)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As was &lt;a href=&quot;/2024/05/15/tor-2024-gpn-22-monerokon-4.html&quot;&gt;previously announced&lt;/a&gt;, Rose, yanmaani, Hugo, and I (Jeremy Rand) represented Namecoin at three conferences in Europe. This was an excellent series of events for a number of reasons, not least the fact that this is the first time we’ve ever had 4 Namecoin developers attending a single conference (our previous record was 3 developers, at 37C3). Expanding our team size has been a priority for a while, and it’s great to see that this is starting to pay off. Of course, there were major substantive benefits as well. As usual for conferences that Namecoiners attend, we engaged in a large number of conversations with other attendees.  Also as usual, we won’t be publicly disclosing the content of those conversations, because I want people to be able to talk to us at conferences without worrying that off-the-cuff comments will be broadcast to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes/slides for Namecoin’s sessions at the Tor meeting, and recordings of Namecoin’s sessions at GPN and MoneroKon, are published below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tor-lisbon-2024-self-authenticating-tls-certificates-for-onion-services-using-a-pkcs11-module&quot;&gt;Tor Lisbon 2024: Self-authenticating TLS Certificates for Onion Services using a PKCS#11 module&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facilitator: Jeremy Rand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onion services are self-authenticating. It is highly unfortunate that this isn’t presently the case for their TLS certificates. ahf already made a proof of concept for using onion service Ed25519 keys as a TLS CA, but this requires substantial browser modifications, both to the trust logic (browsers don’t know they should trust these keys) and to the crypto support (browsers don’t support EdDSA). However, there is hope! Mainstream browsers (including Firefox and Chromium) actually do expose APIs that (with a little creativity) can enable validating TLS certificates based on onion service keys. You don’t even need to recompile the browser. Let’s discuss the implications of this, and maybe make some plans!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.torproject.org/tpo/team/-/wikis/Meetings/2024/Lisbon/self-auth-certs-for-onion-services&quot;&gt;Notes and slides are here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tor-lisbon-2024-pluggable-transport-executables-compression&quot;&gt;Tor Lisbon 2024: Pluggable Transport Executables Compression&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facilitators: Jeremy Rand, Morgan Ava&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The download size of Tor Browser is somewhat larger than would be ideal (even causing rejection in the Android Play Store recently). The Go-based pluggable transports take up a nontrivial portion. A potential solution lies within the well-regarded u-root project (a spin-off of Coreboot that one of Tor’s interns worked with recently). u-root includes a subproject called Go-Busybox, which can merge multiple Go executables into one meta-executable, thus de-duplicating library code via the standard compiler optimization process. Our initial experiments have shown significant space savings, and the savings further compound if Namecoin naming (which also uses Go) is included in the Tor Browser binaries. Is this a fruitful line of inquiry? Are there security implications that we should consider? Are there other tricks we can use to decrease the size of the PT binaries? Let’s discuss!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.torproject.org/tpo/team/-/wikis/Meetings/2024/Lisbon/pluggable-transport-executables-compression&quot;&gt;Notes and slides are here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tor-lisbon-2024-refreshing-best-practices-guidelines-for-tor-friendly-applications&quot;&gt;Tor Lisbon 2024: Refreshing Best Practices Guidelines for Tor-Friendly Applications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facilitators: Jeremy Rand, Morgan Ava&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, some community members wrote up a Tor-Friendly Applications Best Practices document. The document has proven to be valuable, but parts are underspecified, and other parts will need revamping for Arti. This session is to refresh the document. Bring your ideas for things that Tor-friendly applications should do, and your horror stories of things Tor-friendly applications shouldn’t do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.torproject.org/tpo/team/-/wikis/Meetings/2024/Lisbon/refreshing-best-practices-guidelines-for-tor-friendly-applications&quot;&gt;Notes are here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gpn-22-self-authenticating-tls-certificates-for-tor-onion-services&quot;&gt;GPN 22: Self-Authenticating TLS Certificates for Tor Onion Services&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jeremy Rand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TLS (the security layer behind HTTPS) and Tor onion services (anonymously hosted TCP services) are both excellent protocols. Wouldn’t it be nice if we could use them together? In this talk, I’ll cover a working implementation of combining TLS with onion services, without compromising on the security properties that each provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topics to be covered include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why would you want to combine TLS with onion services? Why isn’t onion service encryption good enough?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why isn’t unauthenticated TLS (e.g. self-signed certificates) good enough for onion services?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can we authenticate a TLS certificate for a .onion domain without relying on public CA’s like Let’s Encrypt or any other trusted third parties? (No we’re not using a blockchain.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can we teach standard (unmodified) web browsers like Firefox to apply different certificate validation logic for .onion certificates?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can we teach standard (unmodified) web browsers like Firefox to validate certificates using typically-unsupported elliptic curves like Ed25519 (which Tor uses)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://media.ccc.de/v/gpn22-469-self-authenticating-tls-certificates-for-tor-onion-services&quot;&gt;Video is here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;monerokon-4-human-meaningful-trustless-anonymous-monero-addresses-with-namecoin&quot;&gt;MoneroKon 4: Human-Meaningful, Trustless, Anonymous Monero Addresses with Namecoin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jeremy Rand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monero addresses are already long and unwieldy, and they’re about to get longer with Jamtis. Namecoin is a DNS-like naming system implemented as the first project forked from Bitcoin, predating Monero by 3 years to the day. This talk will cover using Namecoin as a human-meaningful naming layer for Monero addresses, recent anonymity advances that make Namecoin’s privacy more suitable for this use case, how OpenAlias fits in, and how Namecoin compares to the MoneroDNS approach of creating a Monero sidechain for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qQ4ptuh_w84&quot;&gt;Video is here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge thank you to the following groups who facilitated our participation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cyphrs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://replicant.us/&quot;&gt;The Replicant Assembly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cypherpunks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re hoping to return to these events next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s Internet Hardening Fund and Cyphrs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/07/24/tor-2024-gpn-22-monerokon-4-summary.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/07/24/tor-2024-gpn-22-monerokon-4-summary.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reducing Size With Concise Binary Object Representation (CBOR) and Name Gifting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Several new Electrum-NMC enhancements have been added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;minimizing-size-with-concise-binary-object-representation-cbor&quot;&gt;Minimizing Size with Concise Binary Object Representation (CBOR)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incorporating Concise Binary Object Representation (CBOR) offers significant advantages, including reduced data size and improved efficiency. Currently, to use CBOR, you need to convert your JSON data into CBOR format and paste the hex equivalent into the hex tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/Configure-Name-Dialog-Hex-2024-05-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;Binary Encoding (value)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this process can be a bit confusing, we are working to simplify it by providing an avenue to do the conversion directly within Electrum-NMC. Once you’ve pasted the CBOR hex data, you can confirm its validity by parsing it and displaying its contents in the DNS builder dialog, by clicking the DNS Editor button, you’ll see the different records contained in the CBOR data.  Unfortunately, if you parse your CBOR hex data, you’ll need to paste it again in the hex tab, but we’re actively working to streamline this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the addition of CBOR support in ncdns, after registering a name with a CBOR encoded value, ncdns should be able to parse and provide the DNS records associated with that name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gifting-names&quot;&gt;Gifting Names&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to requesting a payment, you can now also request a name. When registering a name that is available, you’ll see an extra button and field to request someone to pay for it on your behalf. Additionally, there is an extra field where you can add an additional amount to your request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/Buy-Name-Request-Name.png&quot; alt=&quot;Request Name (value)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After clicking the “Request Registration” button, a UI with your request will be displayed, similar to what is seen in the request tab. From there, you can send the request URL or QR code to the recipient &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;(gifter)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/Request-Name-UI-Tabs.png&quot; alt=&quot;Request Name Tabs (value)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gifter can now paste the payment URL in the receive tab or use the QR code. The details will be automatically populated, allowing the gifter to proceed with the payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/Send-UI-Request-Name.png&quot; alt=&quot;Send Tab (value)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After your invoice is settled, you simply need to proceed with the normal name registration process. You’ll only be required to pay minimal update fees, as the name has already been paid for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/files/videos/docs/gifting/gifting.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot; /&gt;
Demo video of Gifting Names in Electrum-NMC.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s NGI Assure Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/05/17/cbor-and-gifting-names.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/05/17/cbor-and-gifting-names.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin will be at Tor Meeting 2024, GPN 22, and MoneroKon 4</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re happy to announce that Namecoin developers will be at multiple conferences over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eweiibe6tdjsdprb4px6rqrzzcsi22m4koia44kc5pcjr7nec2rlxyad.onion/tpo/team/-/wikis/Meetings/2024/Lisbon&quot;&gt;Tor Meeting 2024&lt;/a&gt; in Lisbon, Portugal (May 20-24): Jeremy Rand will represent Namecoin during the main event; Jeremy Rand, Rose Turing, and Yanmaani will represent Namecoin during Community Day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://entropia.de/GPN22/en&quot;&gt;GPN 22&lt;/a&gt; in Karlsruhe, Germany (May 30 - June 2): Jeremy Rand and Rose Turing will represent Namecoin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://monerokon.org/&quot;&gt;MoneroKon 4&lt;/a&gt; in Prague, Czechia (June 7-9): Jeremy Rand, Rose Turing, and Yanmaani will represent Namecoin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, schedules are not yet finalized, but details should be posted soon on the respective conferences’ websites. (We expect to host sessions at Tor, GPN, and MoneroKon). If you’re near any of these events and would like to meet up to discuss collaboration, please ping us on #namecoin-dev.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank Cyphrs, Replicant, and Cypherpunks for facilitating our participation at these conferences. See you there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/05/15/tor-2024-gpn-22-monerokon-4.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/05/15/tor-2024-gpn-22-monerokon-4.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Electrum-NMC AppArmor, Static Analysis, and Input Validation + ncdns Unix Sockets</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Several new Electrum-NMC &amp;amp; ncdns enhancements have been added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apparmor-profiles-for-electrum-nmc&quot;&gt;AppArmor Profiles for Electrum-NMC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AppArmor is a Mandatory Access Control (MAC) system which confines programs to a limited set of resources. AppArmor confinement is provided via profiles loaded into the kernel.
By using AppArmor profiles, we can ensure that Electrum-NMC operates within a predefined security policy, reducing the risk of unauthorized access or malicious actions.
The profiles are provided in the contrib folder. For more information on AppArmor, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubuntu.com/tutorials/beginning-apparmor-profile-development#1-overview&quot;&gt;visit their website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;input-validation-in-electrum-nmcs-dns-builder-gui&quot;&gt;Input Validation in Electrum-NMC’s DNS Builder GUI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When passing data to the DNS Builder, certain validations are performed to offer hints and warnings about invalid data or outdated methods (such as algorithms).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/DNS-Builder-IP-Validation-2024.png&quot; alt=&quot;IP Validation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/DNS-Builder-Algorithm-Validation-2024.png&quot; alt=&quot;IPFS Images&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;static-analysis-testing&quot;&gt;Static Analysis Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We run static analysis using tools such as Flake8, MyPy, and Pylint, comparing results with Electrum (Bitcoin version) to focus on Electrum-NMC-specific issues. This process, integrated into our CI, helps catch bugs early. Looking to contribute? Static analysis issues provide good first-time issues!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enabling-ncdns-to-perform-rpc-requests-via-unix-domain-sockets&quot;&gt;Enabling ncdns to Perform RPC Requests via Unix Domain Sockets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enabling ncdns to perform RPC requests via Unix domain sockets offers a more secure communication method than TCP/IP. To utilize a Unix domain socket, specify it in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;namecoinrpcaddress&lt;/code&gt; field as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;unix:// + &quot;your unix socket path&quot;&lt;/code&gt; such as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;unix:///tmp/test.XXXX&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Namecoin Core supports only TCP/IP, we’ll redirect RPC requests from the Unix Socket to Namecoin Core. This can be achieved using a commnad such as socat command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;socat -d UNIX-LISTEN:&quot;my-unix-socket-path&quot;,fork TCP:&quot;host-address&quot;
socat -d UNIX-LISTEN:/tmp/test.XXXX,fork TCP:localhost:8332
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s NGI Assure Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/05/11/apparmor-static-analysis-input-validation-ncdns-unix-sockets.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rw6nbpjrmcpdxszn3air4bt7t75rpz4cp3c2kbdu72ptua57tzvin4id.onion/2024/05/11/apparmor-static-analysis-input-validation-ncdns-unix-sockets.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
