<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Namecoin</title>
    <description><!--Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
--></description>
    <link>https://namecoin.bit/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://namecoin.bit/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <language>en</language>
    <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 12:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 12:28:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://namecoin.bit/images/logo.png</url>
      <title>Namecoin</title>
      <link>https://namecoin.bit/</link>
      <width>134</width>
      <height>25</height>
    </image>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin's SocksTrace Receives Funding from NLnet Foundation’s NGI0 Core Fund</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re happy to announce that Namecoin is &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnet.nl/news/2024/20241003-announcing-Core-call.html&quot;&gt;receiving&lt;/a&gt; additional funding from NLnet Foundation’s NGI0 Core (Next Generation Internet: Zero Core) Fund. If you’re unfamiliar with NLnet, you might want to read &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnet.nl/foundation/&quot;&gt;about NLnet Foundation&lt;/a&gt;, or just take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://nlnet.nl/thema/index.html&quot;&gt;the projects they’ve funded over the years&lt;/a&gt; (you might see some familiar names).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new funding is focused on SocksTrace. You might know SocksTrace by its former (and truly magical) name, Heteronculous-Horklump. While the former name was hilarious for Harry Potter geeks, we got feedback at 37C3 that it was too… let’s say, “unmemorable” for the rest of the world (especially for non-native English speakers); thus, we’ve seized the chance to simplify things with a name that’s easier on the brain. Don’t worry, though—the new name is still meme-worthy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SocksTrace is a proxy leak detection tool designed for both CI testing and manual QA testing. It leverages the Linux &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ptrace&lt;/code&gt; feature to monitor socket syscalls that could potentially bypass a proxy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the following areas of development will be funded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved speed by whitelisting specific syscalls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Handling incoming TCP (Transmission Control Protocol) connections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improved test coverage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enforce stream isolation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide support for POWER systems&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SOCKSify DNS traffic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work will principally be done by developers Jeremy Rand and Robert Nganga (who is the author of this post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank the awesome people at NLnet Foundation for the continued vote of confidence, as well as the European Commision for their support of the Next Generation Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be posting updates regularly as development proceeds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.bit/2024/10/21/sockstrace-funding-nlnet-ngi0-core.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.bit/2024/10/21/sockstrace-funding-nlnet-ngi0-core.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor Meeting 2024 / GPN 22 / MoneroKon 4 Summary (UPDATED)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As was &lt;a href=&quot;/2024/05/15/tor-2024-gpn-22-monerokon-4.html&quot;&gt;previously announced&lt;/a&gt;, Rose, yanmaani, Hugo, and I (Jeremy Rand) represented Namecoin at three conferences in Europe. This was an excellent series of events for a number of reasons, not least the fact that this is the first time we’ve ever had 4 Namecoin developers attending a single conference (our previous record was 3 developers, at 37C3). Expanding our team size has been a priority for a while, and it’s great to see that this is starting to pay off. Of course, there were major substantive benefits as well. As usual for conferences that Namecoiners attend, we engaged in a large number of conversations with other attendees.  Also as usual, we won’t be publicly disclosing the content of those conversations, because I want people to be able to talk to us at conferences without worrying that off-the-cuff comments will be broadcast to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes/slides for Namecoin’s sessions at the Tor meeting, and recordings of Namecoin’s sessions at GPN and MoneroKon, are published below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tor-lisbon-2024-self-authenticating-tls-certificates-for-onion-services-using-a-pkcs11-module&quot;&gt;Tor Lisbon 2024: Self-authenticating TLS Certificates for Onion Services using a PKCS#11 module&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facilitator: Jeremy Rand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onion services are self-authenticating. It is highly unfortunate that this isn’t presently the case for their TLS certificates. ahf already made a proof of concept for using onion service Ed25519 keys as a TLS CA, but this requires substantial browser modifications, both to the trust logic (browsers don’t know they should trust these keys) and to the crypto support (browsers don’t support EdDSA). However, there is hope! Mainstream browsers (including Firefox and Chromium) actually do expose APIs that (with a little creativity) can enable validating TLS certificates based on onion service keys. You don’t even need to recompile the browser. Let’s discuss the implications of this, and maybe make some plans!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.torproject.org/tpo/team/-/wikis/Meetings/2024/Lisbon/self-auth-certs-for-onion-services&quot;&gt;Notes and slides are here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tor-lisbon-2024-pluggable-transport-executables-compression&quot;&gt;Tor Lisbon 2024: Pluggable Transport Executables Compression&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facilitators: Jeremy Rand, Morgan Ava&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The download size of Tor Browser is somewhat larger than would be ideal (even causing rejection in the Android Play Store recently). The Go-based pluggable transports take up a nontrivial portion. A potential solution lies within the well-regarded u-root project (a spin-off of Coreboot that one of Tor’s interns worked with recently). u-root includes a subproject called Go-Busybox, which can merge multiple Go executables into one meta-executable, thus de-duplicating library code via the standard compiler optimization process. Our initial experiments have shown significant space savings, and the savings further compound if Namecoin naming (which also uses Go) is included in the Tor Browser binaries. Is this a fruitful line of inquiry? Are there security implications that we should consider? Are there other tricks we can use to decrease the size of the PT binaries? Let’s discuss!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.torproject.org/tpo/team/-/wikis/Meetings/2024/Lisbon/pluggable-transport-executables-compression&quot;&gt;Notes and slides are here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tor-lisbon-2024-refreshing-best-practices-guidelines-for-tor-friendly-applications&quot;&gt;Tor Lisbon 2024: Refreshing Best Practices Guidelines for Tor-Friendly Applications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facilitators: Jeremy Rand, Morgan Ava&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, some community members wrote up a Tor-Friendly Applications Best Practices document. The document has proven to be valuable, but parts are underspecified, and other parts will need revamping for Arti. This session is to refresh the document. Bring your ideas for things that Tor-friendly applications should do, and your horror stories of things Tor-friendly applications shouldn’t do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://gitlab.torproject.org/tpo/team/-/wikis/Meetings/2024/Lisbon/refreshing-best-practices-guidelines-for-tor-friendly-applications&quot;&gt;Notes are here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gpn-22-self-authenticating-tls-certificates-for-tor-onion-services&quot;&gt;GPN 22: Self-Authenticating TLS Certificates for Tor Onion Services&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jeremy Rand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TLS (the security layer behind HTTPS) and Tor onion services (anonymously hosted TCP services) are both excellent protocols. Wouldn’t it be nice if we could use them together? In this talk, I’ll cover a working implementation of combining TLS with onion services, without compromising on the security properties that each provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topics to be covered include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why would you want to combine TLS with onion services? Why isn’t onion service encryption good enough?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why isn’t unauthenticated TLS (e.g. self-signed certificates) good enough for onion services?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can we authenticate a TLS certificate for a .onion domain without relying on public CA’s like Let’s Encrypt or any other trusted third parties? (No we’re not using a blockchain.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can we teach standard (unmodified) web browsers like Firefox to apply different certificate validation logic for .onion certificates?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can we teach standard (unmodified) web browsers like Firefox to validate certificates using typically-unsupported elliptic curves like Ed25519 (which Tor uses)?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://media.ccc.de/v/gpn22-469-self-authenticating-tls-certificates-for-tor-onion-services&quot;&gt;Video is here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;monerokon-4-human-meaningful-trustless-anonymous-monero-addresses-with-namecoin&quot;&gt;MoneroKon 4: Human-Meaningful, Trustless, Anonymous Monero Addresses with Namecoin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaker: Jeremy Rand&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monero addresses are already long and unwieldy, and they’re about to get longer with Jamtis. Namecoin is a DNS-like naming system implemented as the first project forked from Bitcoin, predating Monero by 3 years to the day. This talk will cover using Namecoin as a human-meaningful naming layer for Monero addresses, recent anonymity advances that make Namecoin’s privacy more suitable for this use case, how OpenAlias fits in, and how Namecoin compares to the MoneroDNS approach of creating a Monero sidechain for this purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qQ4ptuh_w84&quot;&gt;Video is here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thanks&quot;&gt;Thanks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge thank you to the following groups who facilitated our participation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cyphrs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://replicant.us/&quot;&gt;The Replicant Assembly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cypherpunks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re hoping to return to these events next year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s Internet Hardening Fund and Cyphrs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.bit/2024/07/24/tor-2024-gpn-22-monerokon-4-summary.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.bit/2024/07/24/tor-2024-gpn-22-monerokon-4-summary.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reducing Size With Concise Binary Object Representation (CBOR) and Name Gifting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Several new Electrum-NMC enhancements have been added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;minimizing-size-with-concise-binary-object-representation-cbor&quot;&gt;Minimizing Size with Concise Binary Object Representation (CBOR)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incorporating Concise Binary Object Representation (CBOR) offers significant advantages, including reduced data size and improved efficiency. Currently, to use CBOR, you need to convert your JSON data into CBOR format and paste the hex equivalent into the hex tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/Configure-Name-Dialog-Hex-2024-05-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;Binary Encoding (value)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this process can be a bit confusing, we are working to simplify it by providing an avenue to do the conversion directly within Electrum-NMC. Once you’ve pasted the CBOR hex data, you can confirm its validity by parsing it and displaying its contents in the DNS builder dialog, by clicking the DNS Editor button, you’ll see the different records contained in the CBOR data.  Unfortunately, if you parse your CBOR hex data, you’ll need to paste it again in the hex tab, but we’re actively working to streamline this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the addition of CBOR support in ncdns, after registering a name with a CBOR encoded value, ncdns should be able to parse and provide the DNS records associated with that name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gifting-names&quot;&gt;Gifting Names&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similar to requesting a payment, you can now also request a name. When registering a name that is available, you’ll see an extra button and field to request someone to pay for it on your behalf. Additionally, there is an extra field where you can add an additional amount to your request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/Buy-Name-Request-Name.png&quot; alt=&quot;Request Name (value)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After clicking the “Request Registration” button, a UI with your request will be displayed, similar to what is seen in the request tab. From there, you can send the request URL or QR code to the recipient &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;(gifter)&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/Request-Name-UI-Tabs.png&quot; alt=&quot;Request Name Tabs (value)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gifter can now paste the payment URL in the receive tab or use the QR code. The details will be automatically populated, allowing the gifter to proceed with the payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/Send-UI-Request-Name.png&quot; alt=&quot;Send Tab (value)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After your invoice is settled, you simply need to proceed with the normal name registration process. You’ll only be required to pay minimal update fees, as the name has already been paid for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;https://namecoin.bit/files/videos/docs/gifting/gifting.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot; /&gt;
Demo video of Gifting Names in Electrum-NMC.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s NGI Assure Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.bit/2024/05/17/cbor-and-gifting-names.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.bit/2024/05/17/cbor-and-gifting-names.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin will be at Tor Meeting 2024, GPN 22, and MoneroKon 4</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re happy to announce that Namecoin developers will be at multiple conferences over the next month:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://eweiibe6tdjsdprb4px6rqrzzcsi22m4koia44kc5pcjr7nec2rlxyad.onion/tpo/team/-/wikis/Meetings/2024/Lisbon&quot;&gt;Tor Meeting 2024&lt;/a&gt; in Lisbon, Portugal (May 20-24): Jeremy Rand will represent Namecoin during the main event; Jeremy Rand, Rose Turing, and Yanmaani will represent Namecoin during Community Day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://entropia.de/GPN22/en&quot;&gt;GPN 22&lt;/a&gt; in Karlsruhe, Germany (May 30 - June 2): Jeremy Rand and Rose Turing will represent Namecoin.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://monerokon.org/&quot;&gt;MoneroKon 4&lt;/a&gt; in Prague, Czechia (June 7-9): Jeremy Rand, Rose Turing, and Yanmaani will represent Namecoin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this writing, schedules are not yet finalized, but details should be posted soon on the respective conferences’ websites. (We expect to host sessions at Tor, GPN, and MoneroKon). If you’re near any of these events and would like to meet up to discuss collaboration, please ping us on #namecoin-dev.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d like to thank Cyphrs, Replicant, and Cypherpunks for facilitating our participation at these conferences. See you there!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.bit/2024/05/15/tor-2024-gpn-22-monerokon-4.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.bit/2024/05/15/tor-2024-gpn-22-monerokon-4.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Electrum-NMC AppArmor, Static Analysis, and Input Validation + ncdns Unix Sockets</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Several new Electrum-NMC &amp;amp; ncdns enhancements have been added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apparmor-profiles-for-electrum-nmc&quot;&gt;AppArmor Profiles for Electrum-NMC&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AppArmor is a Mandatory Access Control (MAC) system which confines programs to a limited set of resources. AppArmor confinement is provided via profiles loaded into the kernel.
By using AppArmor profiles, we can ensure that Electrum-NMC operates within a predefined security policy, reducing the risk of unauthorized access or malicious actions.
The profiles are provided in the contrib folder. For more information on AppArmor, &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubuntu.com/tutorials/beginning-apparmor-profile-development#1-overview&quot;&gt;visit their website.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;input-validation-in-electrum-nmcs-dns-builder-gui&quot;&gt;Input Validation in Electrum-NMC’s DNS Builder GUI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When passing data to the DNS Builder, certain validations are performed to offer hints and warnings about invalid data or outdated methods (such as algorithms).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/DNS-Builder-IP-Validation-2024.png&quot; alt=&quot;IP Validation&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/DNS-Builder-Algorithm-Validation-2024.png&quot; alt=&quot;IPFS Images&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;static-analysis-testing&quot;&gt;Static Analysis Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We run static analysis using tools such as Flake8, MyPy, and Pylint, comparing results with Electrum (Bitcoin version) to focus on Electrum-NMC-specific issues. This process, integrated into our CI, helps catch bugs early. Looking to contribute? Static analysis issues provide good first-time issues!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enabling-ncdns-to-perform-rpc-requests-via-unix-domain-sockets&quot;&gt;Enabling ncdns to Perform RPC Requests via Unix Domain Sockets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enabling ncdns to perform RPC requests via Unix domain sockets offers a more secure communication method than TCP/IP. To utilize a Unix domain socket, specify it in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;namecoinrpcaddress&lt;/code&gt; field as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;unix:// + &quot;your unix socket path&quot;&lt;/code&gt; such as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;unix:///tmp/test.XXXX&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Namecoin Core supports only TCP/IP, we’ll redirect RPC requests from the Unix Socket to Namecoin Core. This can be achieved using a commnad such as socat command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;socat -d UNIX-LISTEN:&quot;my-unix-socket-path&quot;,fork TCP:&quot;host-address&quot;
socat -d UNIX-LISTEN:/tmp/test.XXXX,fork TCP:localhost:8332
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s NGI Assure Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.bit/2024/05/11/apparmor-static-analysis-input-validation-ncdns-unix-sockets.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.bit/2024/05/11/apparmor-static-analysis-input-validation-ncdns-unix-sockets.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>rust-electrum-client for Namecoin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I needed to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/bitcoindevkit/rust-electrum-client&quot;&gt;rust-electrum-client&lt;/a&gt; with Namecoin. I was kind of worried that this would be nontrivial, but as it turned out, I was able to get it working in just a few days of hacking, despite this being my first foray into Rust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main incompatibility that came up was that Namecoin headers have an AuxPoW header after the 80-byte Bitcoin-style header, and the deserialization functions in rust-electrum-client really didn’t like that trailing data. There were two deserialization functions that I had to patch to truncate the headers at 80 bytes, which got header parsing to work properly. My current patches are very unclean, and are not really suitable for publication, but I’m planning to clean them up and publish patches over the next few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this was done, a few non-code workarounds were additionally needed (more on these later!), and I was then able to use a real-world rust-electrum-client application with Namecoin. I’ll talk more in a future post about what downstream code is using this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by Cyphrs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.bit/2024/05/10/rust-electrum-client-for-namecoin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.bit/2024/05/10/rust-electrum-client-for-namecoin.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Video, Slides, and Paper from Namecoin at GCER 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is a bit late, but I represented Namecoin at the 2022 Global Conference on Educational Robotics.  Although GCER doesn’t produce official recordings of their talks, I was able to obtain an amateur recording of my talk from an audience member.  I’ve also posted my slides, as well as my paper from the conference proceedings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should be noted that, as this is an amateur recording, the audio quality is not spectacular.  It should also be noted that the audience is rather different from the audiences for whom I usually give Namecoin talks; as a result, the focus of the content is also rather different from my usual Namecoin talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;https://namecoin.bit/files/videos/gcer-2022/Namecoin-GCER-2022-720p.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot; /&gt;
Video of Namecoin at GCER 2022.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/resources/presentations/GCER_2022/Namecoin_GCER_2022_Slides.pdf&quot;&gt;My slides are available here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/resources/presentations/GCER_2022/Namecoin_GCER_2022_Paper.pdf&quot;&gt;My paper is available here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huge thanks to the staff and volunteers from KISS Institute for Practical Robotics, who organized GCER.  Also huge thanks to Helene Myers for the recording.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.bit/2024/05/09/gcer-2022-video.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.bit/2024/05/09/gcer-2022-video.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Enhancements to IPFS &amp; IPNS: A Closer Look at the Latest Updates</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Several new Electrum-NMC enhancements have been added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-dedicated-gui-for-ipfs--ipns&quot;&gt;The Dedicated GUI for IPFS &amp;amp; IPNS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, interacting with IPFS required the creation of TXT records and knowledge of IPFS DNSLink. However, with the introduction of a dedicated GUI, users now have a more user-friendly option, available in the address tab. To learn more about DNSLink and its use of DNS TXT records to map names to IPFS addresses or IPNS names, refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.ipfs.tech/concepts/dnslink/&quot;&gt;IPFS DNS documentation.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/DNS-Builder-IPFS-2024-05-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;IPFS Images&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;video controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;
&lt;source src=&quot;https://namecoin.bit/files/videos/docs/ipfs/brave-ipfs.webm&quot; type=&quot;video/webm&quot; /&gt;
Demo video of Namecoin + IPFS in Brave.
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;added-option-for-value-encoding&quot;&gt;Added Option for Value Encoding&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When registering names, there is now an option to pass values as binary, encoded in hexadecimal format. This enhancement provides greater flexibility and control for developers and power users, allowing them to represent domain name values in a more efficient and versatile manner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/screenshots/electrum-nmc/Configure-Name-Dialog-Hex-2024-05-01.png&quot; alt=&quot;Binary Encoding (value)&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gui-testing&quot;&gt;GUI Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For GUI testing, we validate the GUI form’s build process and execute regression tests, which helps us identify any errors in the files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;windows-binaries-testing&quot;&gt;Windows Binaries Testing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We validate the integrity of the build process and conduct regression tests on these binaries to ensure their functionality and detect any potential issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s NGI Assure Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.bit/2024/05/01/ipfs-value-binary-encoding.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.bit/2024/05/01/ipfs-value-binary-encoding.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Robert Nganga</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Electrum-NMC v4.0.6 Released</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve released Electrum-NMC v4.0.6. The changelog will probably be posted after 37C3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As usual, you can download it at the &lt;a href=&quot;/download/betas/#electrum-nmc&quot;&gt;Beta Downloads page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This work was funded by NLnet Foundation’s NGI0 Discovery Fund.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.bit/2023/12/23/electrum-nmc-v4.0.6-released.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.bit/2023/12/23/electrum-nmc-v4.0.6-released.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>Releases</category>
        
        <category>Electrum Releases</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Namecoin will be at 37C3</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After a lengthy pandemic-induced hiatus, C3 is finally back this year, and we’re happy to announce that three Namecoin developers will be at &lt;a href=&quot;https://events.ccc.de/congress/2023/wiki/index.php/Main_Page&quot;&gt;37C3 (the 37th Chaos Communication Congress)&lt;/a&gt; in Hamburg, December 27-30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excitingly, one of our developers in attendance (Hugo Landau) will be giving a talk in the main track (not a Cluster track); &lt;a href=&quot;https://fahrplan.events.ccc.de/congress/2023/fahrplan/events/11781.html&quot;&gt;the details for that talk are here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We expect to give some additional talks and workshops at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://decentral.community/&quot;&gt;Critical Decentralization Cluster (CDC)&lt;/a&gt;, however, the details of those events are still in flux and will probably not be announced until shortly before the beginning of the Congress; keep an eye on &lt;a href=&quot;https://frab.riat.at/en/37c3/public/schedule&quot;&gt;the CDC schedule&lt;/a&gt;. Recordings and live-streams may happen as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, Namecoin has participated in C3 as a Project of the Monero Assembly. We’re excited to announce that this year, Namecoin has been upgraded to a full Assembly of our own. Namecoin and Monero remain excellent friends, but everyone agreed that this year, the time was right for us to branch out as an independent Assembly. Also thanks go out to our friends at &lt;a href=&quot;https://replicant.us/&quot;&gt;The Replicant Assembly&lt;/a&gt;, who are once again facilitating Namecoin’s participation. We’re looking forward to the Congress!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://namecoin.bit/2023/12/21/37c3.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://namecoin.bit/2023/12/21/37c3.html</guid>
        <dc:creator>Jeremy Rand</dc:creator>
        
        <category>News</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
